A O
MOVE O
to O
stop O
Mr. O
Gaitskell B-PERSON
from O
nominating O
any O
more O
Labour B-ORGANIZATION
life O
Peers O
is O
to O
be O
made O
at O
a O
meeting O
of O
Labour B-ORGANIZATION
M Ps O
tomorrow B-TIME
. O

Mr. O
Michael B-PERSON
Foot I-PERSON
has O
put O
down O
a O
resolution O
on O
the O
subject O
and O
he O
is O
to O
be O
backed O
by O
Mr. O
Will B-PERSON
Griffiths I-PERSON
, O
M P O
for O
Manchester B-ORGANIZATION
Exchange I-ORGANIZATION
. O

A O
MOVE O
to O
stop O
Mr. O
Gaitskell B-PERSON
from O
nominating O
any O
more O
Labour B-ORGANIZATION
life O
Peers O
is O
to O
be O
made O
at O
a O
meeting O
of O
Labour B-ORGANIZATION
0M Ps O
tomorrow B-TIME
. O

Mr. O
Michael B-PERSON
Foot I-PERSON
has O
put O
down O
a O
resolution O
on O
the O
subject O
and O
he O
is O
to O
be O
backed O
by O
Mr. O
Will B-PERSON
Griffiths I-PERSON
, O
0M P O
for O
Manchester B-ORGANIZATION
Exchange I-ORGANIZATION
. O

Though O
they O
may O
gather O
some O
Left-wing O
support O
, O
a O
large O
majority O
of O
Labour B-ORGANIZATION
M Ps O
are O
likely O
to O
turn O
down O
the O
Foot-Griffiths O
resolution O
. O

Mr. O
Foot's B-PERSON
line O
will O
be O
that O
as O
Labour B-ORGANIZATION
M Ps O
opposed O
the O
Government O
Bill O
which O
brought O
life O
peers O
into O
existence O
, O
they O
should O
not O
now O
put O
forward O
nominees O
. O

He O
believes O
that O
the O
House B-ORGANIZATION
of I-ORGANIZATION
Lords I-ORGANIZATION
should O
be O
abolished O
and O
that O
Labour B-ORGANIZATION
should O
not O
take O
any O
steps O
which O
would O
appear O
to O
" O
prop O
up O
" O
an O
out-dated O
institution O
. O

Though O
they O
may O
gather O
some O
Left-wing O
support O
, O
a O
large O
majority O
of O
Labour B-ORGANIZATION
M Ps O
are O
likely O
to O
turn O
down O
the O
Foot- O
Griffiths O
resolution O
. O

Mr. O
Foot's B-PERSON
line O
will O
be O
that O
as O
Labour B-ORGANIZATION
M Ps O
opposed O
the O
Government O
Bill O
which O
brought O
life O
peers O
into O
existence O
, O
they O
should O
not O
now O
put O
forward O
nominees O
. O

He O
believes O
that O
the O
House B-ORGANIZATION
of I-ORGANIZATION
Lords I-ORGANIZATION
should O
be O
abolished O
and O
that O
Labour B-ORGANIZATION
should O
not O
take O
any O
steps O
which O
would O
appear O
to O
" O
prop O
up O
" O
an O
out- O
Though O
they O
may O
gather O
some O
Left-wing O
support O
, O
a O
large O
majority O
of O
Labour B-ORGANIZATION
0M Ps O
are O
likely O
to O
turn O
down O
the O
Foot-Griffiths B-PERSON
resolution O
. O

Mr. O
Foot's B-PERSON
line O
will O
be O
that O
as O
Labour B-ORGANIZATION
0M Ps O
opposed O
the O
Govern- O
ment O
Bill O
which O
brought O
life O
peers O
into O
existence O
, O
they O
should O
not O
now O
put O
forward O
nominees O
. O

He O
believes O
that O
the O
House B-ORGANIZATION
of I-ORGANIZATION
Lords I-ORGANIZATION
should O
be O
abolished O
and O
that O
Labour B-ORGANIZATION
should O
not O
take O
any O
steps O
which O
would O
appear O
to O
" O
prop O
up O
" O
an O
out-dated O
institution O
. O

Since O
1958 B-TIME
, O
13 B-CARDINAL
Labour B-ORGANIZATION
life O
Peers O
and O
Peeresses O
have O
been O
created O
. O

Most O
Labour B-ORGANIZATION
sentiment O
would O
 O
still O
favour O
the O
abolition O
of O
the O
House B-ORGANIZATION
of I-ORGANIZATION
Lords I-ORGANIZATION
, O
but O
while O
it O
remains O
Labour B-ORGANIZATION
has O
to O
have O
an O
adequate O
number O
of O
members O
. O

THE O
two B-CARDINAL
rival O
African B-NORP
Nationalist O
Parties O
of O
Northern B-LOCATION
Rhodesia I-LOCATION
have O
agreed O
to O
get O
together O
to O
face O
the O
challenge O
from O
Sir O
Roy B-PERSON
Welensky I-PERSON
, O
the O
Federal O
Premier O
. O

Since O
1958 B-TIME
, O
13 B-CARDINAL
Labour B-ORGANIZATION
life O
Peers O
and O
Peeresses O
have O
been O
created O
. O

Most O
Labour B-ORGANIZATION
sentiment O
would O
still O
favour O
the O
abolition O
of O
the O
House B-ORGANIZATION
of I-ORGANIZATION
Lords I-ORGANIZATION
, O
but O
while O
it O
remains O
Labour B-ORGANIZATION
has O
to O
have O
an O
adequate O
number O
of O
members O
. O

THE O
two B-CARDINAL
rival O
African B-NORP
Nationalist O
Parties O
of O
Northern B-LOCATION
Rhodesia I-LOCATION
have O
agreed O
to O
get O
together O
to O
face O
the O
challenge O
from O
Sir O
Roy B-PERSON
Welensky I-PERSON
, O
the O
Federal O
Premier O
. O

Since O
1958 B-TIME
, O
13 B-CARDINAL
Labour B-ORGANIZATION
life O
Peers O
and O
 O
Peeresses O
have O
been O
created O
. O

Most O
Labour B-ORGANIZATION
sentiment O
would O
still O
favour O
the O
abolition O
of O
the O
House B-ORGANIZATION
of I-ORGANIZATION
Lords I-ORGANIZATION
, O
but O
while O
it O
remains O
Labour B-ORGANIZATION
has O
to O
have O
an O
adequate O
number O
of O
members O
. O

THE O
two B-CARDINAL
rival O
African B-NORP
Nationalist O
Parties O
of O
Northern B-LOCATION
Rhodesia I-LOCATION
have O
agreed O
to O
get O
together O
to O
face O
the O
challenge O
from O
Sir O
Roy B-PERSON
Welensky I-PERSON
, O
the O
Federal O
Premier O
. O

Delegates O
from O
Mr. O
Kenneth B-PERSON
Kaunda's I-PERSON
United B-ORGANIZATION
National I-ORGANIZATION
Independence I-ORGANIZATION
Party I-ORGANIZATION
( O
280,000 B-CARDINAL
members O
) O
and O
Mr. O
Harry B-PERSON
Nkumbula's I-PERSON
African B-ORGANIZATION
National I-ORGANIZATION
Congress I-ORGANIZATION
( O
400,000 B-CARDINAL
) O
will O
meet O
in O
London B-LOCATION
today B-TIME
to O
discuss O
a O
common O
course O
of O
action O
. O

Sir O
Roy B-PERSON
is O
violently O
opposed O
to O
Africans B-NORP
getting O
an O
elected O
majority O
in O
Northern B-LOCATION
Rhodesia I-LOCATION
, O
but O
the O
Colonial O
Secretary O
, O
Mr. O
Iain B-PERSON
Macleod I-PERSON
, O
is O
insisting O
on O
a O
policy O
of O
change O
. O

Delegates O
from O
Mr. O
Kenneth B-PERSON
Kaunda's I-PERSON
United B-ORGANIZATION
National I-ORGANIZATION
Independence I-ORGANIZATION
Party I-ORGANIZATION
( O
280,000 B-CARDINAL
members O
) O
and O
Mr. O
Harry B-PERSON
Nkumbula's I-PERSON
African B-ORGANIZATION
National I-ORGANIZATION
Congress I-ORGANIZATION
( O
400,000 B-CARDINAL
) O
will O
meet O
in O
London B-LOCATION
today B-TIME
to O
discuss O
a O
common O
course O
of O
action O
. O

Sir O
Roy B-PERSON
is O
violently O
opposed O
to O
Africans B-NORP
getting O
an O
elected O
majority O
in O
Northern B-LOCATION
Rhodesia I-LOCATION
, O
but O
the O
Colonial O
Secretary O
, O
Mr. O
Iain B-PERSON
Macleod I-PERSON
, O
is O
insisting O
on O
a O
policy O
of O
change O
. O

Delegates O
from O
Mr. O
Kenneth B-PERSON
Kaunda's I-PERSON
United B-ORGANIZATION
National I-ORGANIZATION
Independence I-ORGANIZATION
Party I-ORGANIZATION
( O
280,000 B-CARDINAL
members O
) O
and O
Mr. O
Harry B-PERSON
Nkumbula's I-PERSON
African B-ORGANIZATION
National I-ORGANIZATION
Congress I-ORGANIZATION
( O
400,000 B-CARDINAL
) O
will O
meet O
in O
London B-LOCATION
today B-TIME
to O
discuss O
a O
common O
course O
of O
action O
. O

Sir O
Roy B-PERSON
is O
violently O
opposed O
to O
Africans B-NORP
getting O
an O
elected O
majority O
in O
Northern B-LOCATION
Rhodesia I-LOCATION
, O
but O
the O
Colonial O
Secretary O
, O
Mr. O
Iain B-PERSON
Macleod I-PERSON
, O
is O
insisting O
on O
a O
policy O
of O
change O
. O

Sir O
Roy's B-PERSON
United B-ORGANIZATION
Federal I-ORGANIZATION
Party I-ORGANIZATION
is O
boycotting O
the O
London B-LOCATION
talks O
on O
the O
Protectorate's O
future O
. O

Said O
Mr. O
Nkumbula B-PERSON
last B-TIME
night I-TIME
: O
" O
We O
want O
to O
discuss O
what O
to O
do O
if O
the O
British B-ORGANIZATION
Government I-ORGANIZATION
gives O
in O
to O
Sir O
Roy B-PERSON
and O
the O
talks O
fall O
through O
. O

There O
are O
bound O
to O
be O
demonstrations O
. O

" O
Yesterday B-TIME
Sir O
Roy's B-PERSON
chief O
aide O
, O
Mr. O
Julius B-PERSON
Greenfield I-PERSON
, O
telephoned O
his O
chief O
a O
report O
on O
his O
talks O
with O
Mr. O
Macmillan B-PERSON
at O
Chequers B-LOCATION
. O

Sir O
Roy's B-PERSON
United B-ORGANIZATION
Federal I-ORGANIZATION
Party I-ORGANIZATION
is O
boycotting O
the O
London B-LOCATION
talks O
on O
the O
Protectorate's O
future O
. O

Said O
Mr. O
Nkumbula B-PERSON
last B-TIME
night I-TIME
: O
" O
We O
want O
to O
discuss O
what O
to O
do O
if O
the O
British B-NORP
demonstrations O
. O

" O
Yesterday B-TIME
Sir O
Roy's B-PERSON
chief O
aide O
, O
Mr. O
Julius B-PERSON
Greenfield I-PERSON
, O
telephoned O
his O
chief O
a O
report O
on O
his O
talks O
with O
Mr. O
Macmillan B-PERSON
at O
Chequers B-LOCATION
. O

Sir O
Roy's B-PERSON
United B-ORGANIZATION
Federal I-ORGANIZATION
Party I-ORGANIZATION
is O
boycotting O
the O
London B-LOCATION
talks O
on O
the O
Protectorate's O
future O
. O

Said O
Mr. O
Nkumbula B-PERSON
last B-TIME
night I-TIME
: O
" O
We O
want O
to O
discuss O
what O
to O
do O
if O
the O
British B-ORGANIZATION
Government I-ORGANIZATION
gives O
in O
to O
Sir O
Roy B-PERSON
and O
the O
talks O
fall O
through O
. O

There O
are O
bound O
to O
be O
demonstrations O
. O

" O
Yesterday B-TIME
Sir O
Roy's B-PERSON
chief O
aide O
, O
Mr. O
Julius B-PERSON
Greenfield I-PERSON
, O
telephoned O
his O
chief O
a O
report O
on O
his O
talks O
with O
Mr. O
Macmillan B-PERSON
at O
Chequers B-LOCATION
. O

Mr. O
Macleod B-PERSON
went O
on O
with O
the O
conference O
at O
Lancaster B-LOCATION
House I-LOCATION
despite O
the O
crisis O
which O
had O
blown O
up O
. O

He O
has O
now O
revealed O
his O
full O
plans O
to O
the O
Africans B-NORP
and O
Liberals B-NORP
attending O
. O

These O
plans O
do O
not O
give O
the O
Africans B-NORP
the O
overall O
majority O
they O
are O
seeking O
. O

African B-NORP
delegates O
are O
studying O
them O
today B-TIME
. O

The O
conference O
will O
meet O
to O
discuss O
the O
function O
of O
a O
proposed O
House B-ORGANIZATION
of I-ORGANIZATION
Chiefs I-ORGANIZATION
. O

Mr. O
Macleod B-PERSON
went O
on O
with O
the O
conference O
at O
Lancaster B-LOCATION
House I-LOCATION
despite O
the O
crisis O
which O
had O
blown O
up O
. O

He O
has O
now O
revealed O
his O
full O
plans O
to O
the O
Africans B-NORP
and O
Liberals B-NORP
attending O
. O

These O
plans O
do O
not O
give O
the O
Africans B-NORP
the O
overall O
majority O
they O
are O
seeking O
. O

African B-NORP
delegates O
are O
studying O
them O
today B-TIME
. O

The O
conference O
will O
meet O
to O
discuss O
the O
function O
of O
a O
proposed O
House B-ORGANIZATION
of I-ORGANIZATION
Chiefs I-ORGANIZATION
. O

Mr. O
Macleod B-PERSON
went O
on O
with O
the O
conference O
at O
Lancaster B-LOCATION
House I-LOCATION
despite O
the O
crisis O
which O
had O
blown O
up O
. O

He O
has O
now O
revealed O
his O
full O
plans O
to O
the O
Africans B-NORP
and O
Liberals B-NORP
attending O
. O

These O
plans O
do O
not O
give O
the O
Africans B-NORP
the O
overall O
majo- O
rity O
they O
are O
seeking O
. O

African B-NORP
delegates O
are O
studying O
them O
today B-TIME
. O

The O
conference O
will O
meet O
to O
discuss O
the O
function O
of O
a O
proposed O
House B-ORGANIZATION
of I-ORGANIZATION
Chiefs I-ORGANIZATION
. O

MR. O
IAIN B-PERSON
MACLEOD I-PERSON
, O
the O
Colonial O
Secretary O
, O
denied O
in O
the O
Commons B-ORGANIZATION
last B-TIME
night I-TIME
that O
there O
have O
been O
secret O
negotiations O
on O
Northern B-LOCATION
Rhodesia's I-LOCATION
future O
. O

The O
Northern B-LOCATION
Rhodesia I-LOCATION
conference O
in O
London B-LOCATION
has O
been O
boycotted O
by O
the O
two B-CARDINAL
main O
settlers' O
parties O
- O
the O
United B-ORGANIZATION
Federal I-ORGANIZATION
Party I-ORGANIZATION
and O
the O
Dominion B-ORGANIZATION
Party I-ORGANIZATION
. O

But O
representatives O
of O
Sir O
Roy B-PERSON
Welensky I-PERSON
, O
Prime O
Minister O
of O
the O
Central B-ORGANIZATION
African I-ORGANIZATION
Federation I-ORGANIZATION
, O
went O
to O
Chequers B-LOCATION
at B-TIME
the I-TIME
week-end I-TIME
for O
talks O
with O
Mr. O
Macmillan B-PERSON
. O

MR. O
IAIN B-PERSON
MACLEOD I-PERSON
, O
the O
Colonial O
Secretary O
, O
denied O
in O
the O
Commons B-ORGANIZATION
last B-TIME
night I-TIME
that O
there O
have O
been O
secret O
negotiations O
on O
Northern B-LOCATION
Rhodesia's I-LOCATION
future O
. O

The O
Northern B-LOCATION
Rhodesia I-LOCATION
conference O
in O
London B-LOCATION
has O
been O
boycotted O
by O
the O
two B-CARDINAL
main O
settlers' O
parties O
- O
the O
United B-ORGANIZATION
Federal I-ORGANIZATION
Party I-ORGANIZATION
and O
the O
Dominion B-ORGANIZATION
Party I-ORGANIZATION
. O

But O
representatives O
of O
Sir O
Roy B-PERSON
Welensky I-PERSON
, O
Prime O
Minister O
of O
the O
Central B-ORGANIZATION
African I-ORGANIZATION
Federation I-ORGANIZATION
, O
went O
to O
Chequers B-LOCATION
at B-TIME
the I-TIME
week-end I-TIME
for O
talks O
with O
Mr. O
Macmillan B-PERSON
. O

Mr. O
Iain B-PERSON
Macleod I-PERSON
, O
the O
Colonial O
Secretary O
, O
denied O
in O
the O
Commons B-ORGANIZATION
last B-TIME
night I-TIME
that O
there O
have O
been O
secret O
negotiations O
on O
the O
Northern B-LOCATION
Rhodesia's I-LOCATION
future O
. O

The O
Northern B-LOCATION
Rhodesia I-LOCATION
conference O
in O
London B-LOCATION
has O
been O
boycotted O
by O
the O
two B-CARDINAL
main O
settlers' O
parties O
- O
the O
United B-ORGANIZATION
Federal I-ORGANIZATION
Party I-ORGANIZATION
and O
the O
Dominion B-ORGANIZATION
Party I-ORGANIZATION
. O

But O
representatives O
of O
Sir O
Roy B-PERSON
Welensky I-PERSON
, O
Prime O
Minister O
of O
the O
Central B-ORGANIZATION
African I-ORGANIZATION
Federation I-ORGANIZATION
, O
went O
to O
Chequers B-LOCATION
at B-TIME
the I-TIME
week-end I-TIME
for O
talks O
with O
Mr. O
Macmillan B-PERSON
. O

Northern B-LOCATION
Rhodesia I-LOCATION
is O
a O
member O
of O
the O
Federation B-ORGANIZATION
. O

Mr. O
Macleod B-PERSON
was O
not O
at O
the O
week-end B-TIME
meeting O
. O

But O
he O
told O
M Ps O
yesterday B-TIME
: O
" O
I O
have O
no O
knowledge O
of O
secret O
negotiations O
. O

" O
He O
said O
Britain B-LOCATION
had O
an O
obligation O
to O
consult O
the O
Federal B-ORGANIZATION
Government I-ORGANIZATION
. O

But O
the O
final O
decision O
remained O
with O
the O
British B-ORGANIZATION
Government I-ORGANIZATION
. O

Mr. O
James B-PERSON
Callaghan I-PERSON
, O
Labour's B-ORGANIZATION
Colonial O
spokesman O
, O
said O
Sir O
Roy B-PERSON
had O
no O
right O
to O
delay O
progress O
in O
the O
talks O
by O
refusing O
to O
sit O
round O
the O
conference O
table O
. O

Northern B-LOCATION
Rhodesia I-LOCATION
is O
a O
member O
of O
the O
Federation B-ORGANIZATION
. O

Mr. O
Macleod B-PERSON
was O
not O
at O
the O
week-end B-TIME
meeting O
. O

But O
he O
told O
M Ps O
yesterday B-TIME
: O
" O
I O
have O
no O
knowledge O
of O
secret O
negotiations O
. O

" O
He O
said O
Britain B-LOCATION
had O
an O
obligation O
to O
consult O
the O
Federal B-ORGANIZATION
Government I-ORGANIZATION
. O

But O
the O
final O
decision O
remained O
with O
the O
British B-ORGANIZATION
Government I-ORGANIZATION
. O

Mr. O
James B-PERSON
Callaghan I-PERSON
, O
Labour's B-ORGANIZATION
Colonial O
spokesman O
, O
said O
Sir O
Roy B-PERSON
had O
no O
right O
to O
delay O
progress O
in O
the O
talks O
by O
refusing O
to O
sit O
round O
the O
conference O
table O
. O

Northern B-LOCATION
Rhodesia I-LOCATION
is O
a O
member O
of O
the O
Fede- B-ORGANIZATION
ration I-ORGANIZATION
. O

Mr. O
Macleod B-PERSON
was O
not O
at O
the O
week-end B-TIME
meeting O
. O

But O
he O
told O
M Ps O
yesterday B-TIME
: O
" O
I O
have O
no O
knowledge O
of O
secret O
negotiations O
. O

" O
He O
said O
Britain B-LOCATION
had O
an O
obligation O
to O
consult O
the O
Federal B-ORGANIZATION
Government I-ORGANIZATION
. O

Mr. O
James B-PERSON
Callaghan I-PERSON
, O
Labour's B-ORGANIZATION
Colonial O
spokesman O
, O
said O
Sir O
Roy B-PERSON
had O
no O
right O
to O
delay O
progress O
in O
the O
talks O
by O
refusing O
to O
sit O
round O
the O
conference O
table O
. O

Mr. O
Macleod B-PERSON
thought O
the O
two B-CARDINAL
Rhodesian B-NORP
parties O
had O
refused O
to O
attend O
the O
talks O
because O
Sir O
Roy B-PERSON
had O
found O
messages O
sent O
from O
the O
Government B-ORGANIZATION
were O
" O
unsatisfac- O
tory O
. O

" O
African B-ORGANIZATION
delegates O
to O
the O
talks O
yester- B-TIME
day I-TIME
called O
on O
Mr. O
Macmillan B-PERSON
to O
cease O
his O
negotiations O
with O
Sir O
Roy's B-PERSON
representative O
, O
Mr. O
Julius B-PERSON
Greenfield I-PERSON
. O

He O
was O
at O
Che- B-LOCATION
quers I-LOCATION
last B-TIME
week-end I-TIME
. O

They O
said O
they O
regarded O
with O
" O
growing O
anger O
" O
the O
" O
gross O
and O
unconstitutional O
" O
interference O
by O
Sir O
Roy's B-PERSON
Federal B-ORGANIZATION
Government I-ORGANIZATION
in O
the O
talks O
. O

Mr. O
Macleod B-PERSON
thought O
the O
two B-CARDINAL
Rhodesian B-NORP
parties O
had O
refused O
to O
attend O
the O
talks O
because O
Sir O
Roy B-PERSON
had O
found O
messages O
sent O
from O
the O
Government B-ORGANIZATION
were O
" O
unsatisfactory O
. O

" O
African B-NORP
delegates O
to O
the O
talks O
yesterday B-TIME
called O
on O
Mr. O
Macmillan B-PERSON
to O
cease O
his O
negotiations O
with O
Sir O
Roy's B-PERSON
representative O
, O
Mr. O
Julius B-PERSON
Greenfield I-PERSON
. O

He O
was O
at O
Chequers B-LOCATION
last B-TIME
week-end I-TIME
. O

They O
said O
they O
regarded O
with O
" O
growing O
anger O
" O
the O
gross O
and O
unconstitutional O
" O
interference O
by O
Sir O
Roy's B-PERSON
Federal B-ORGANIZATION
Government I-ORGANIZATION
in O
the O
talks O
. O

Informal O
talks O
at O
Lancaster B-LOCATION
House I-LOCATION
will O
resume O
today B-TIME
. O

President O
Kennedy B-PERSON
today B-TIME
defended O
the O
appointment O
of O
a O
Negro B-NORP
as O
his O
Housing O
Minister O
. O

It O
has O
aroused O
strong O
opposition O
from O
the O
anti-Negro B-NORP
senators O
of O
the O
Deep B-LOCATION
South I-LOCATION
. O

The O
negro O
is O
Mr. O
Robert B-PERSON
Weaver I-PERSON
of O
New B-LOCATION
York I-LOCATION
. O

One B-CARDINAL
of O
his O
tasks O
will O
be O
to O
see O
there O
is O
no O
racial O
discrimination O
in O
Government B-ORGANIZATION
and O
State B-ORGANIZATION
housing O
projects O
. O

B.Kaufmann B-PERSON
Informal O
talks O
at O
Lancaster B-LOCATION
House I-LOCATION
will O
resume O
today B-TIME
. O

PRESIDENT O
KENNEDY B-PERSON
today B-TIME
defended O
the O
appointment O
of O
a O
Negro O
as O
his O
Housing O
Minister O
. O

It O
has O
aroused O
strong O
opposition O
from O
the O
anti-Negro O
senators O
of O
the O
Deep B-LOCATION
South I-LOCATION
. O

The O
negro O
is O
Mr. O
Robert B-PERSON
 O
Weaver B-PERSON
of O
New B-LOCATION
York I-LOCATION
. O

One B-CARDINAL
of O
his O
tasks O
will O
be O
to O
see O
there O
is O
no O
racial O
discrimination O
in O
Government B-ORGANIZATION
and O
State B-ORGANIZATION
housing O
projects O
. O

Informal O
talks O
at O
Lancaster B-LOCATION
House I-LOCATION
will O
resume O
today B-TIME
. O

PRESIDENT O
KENNEDY B-PERSON
today B-TIME
defended O
the O
appointment O
of O
a O
Negro O
as O
his O
Housing O
Minister O
. O

It O
has O
aroused O
strong O
opposition O
from O
the O
anti-Negro O
senators O
of O
the O
Deep B-LOCATION
South I-LOCATION
. O

The O
negro O
is O
Mr. O
Robert B-PERSON
Weaver I-PERSON
of O
New B-LOCATION
York I-LOCATION
. O

One B-CARDINAL
of O
his O
tasks O
will O
be O
to O
see O
there O
is O
no O
racial O
discrimination O
in O
Government B-ORGANIZATION
and O
State B-ORGANIZATION
housing O
projects O
. O

Senator O
Allen B-PERSON
Ellender I-PERSON
of O
Louisiana B-LOCATION
sparked O
off O
the O
opposition B-ORGANIZATION
by O
telling O
a O
television O
audience O
it O
was O
" O
current O
Washington B-LOCATION
gossip O
" O
that O
Weaver B-PERSON
once O
had O
Communist B-NORP
affiliations O
. O

The O
Senate B-ORGANIZATION
Banking I-ORGANIZATION
Committee I-ORGANIZATION
, O
which O
is O
headed O
by O
another O
Southern B-NORP
Senator O
- O
Willis B-PERSON
Robertson I-PERSON
, O
of O
Virginia B-LOCATION
- O
met O
today B-TIME
in O
closed O
session O
to O
discuss O
Weaver's B-PERSON
appointment O
. O

Senator O
Robertson B-PERSON
later O
disclosed O
he O
had O
sent O
a O
letter O
to O
Mr. O
Kennedy B-PERSON
saying O
he O
had O
received O
several O
complaints O
about O
Weaver's B-PERSON
loyalty O
. O

Senator O
Allen B-PERSON
Ellender I-PERSON
, O
of O
Louisiana B-LOCATION
, O
sparked O
off O
the O
opposition B-ORGANIZATION
by O
telling O
a O
television O
audience O
it O
was O
" O
current O
Washington B-LOCATION
gossip O
" O
that O
Weaver B-PERSON
once O
had O
Communist B-NORP
affiliations O
. O

The O
Senate B-ORGANIZATION
Banking I-ORGANIZATION
Committee I-ORGANIZATION
, O
which O
is O
headed O
by O
another O
Southern B-NORP
Senator O
- O
Willis B-PERSON
Robertson I-PERSON
, O
of O
Virginia B-LOCATION
- O
met O
today B-TIME
in O
closed O
session O
to O
discuss O
Weaver's B-PERSON
appointment O
. O

Senator O
Robertson B-PERSON
later O
disclosed O
he O
had O
sent O
a O
letter O
to O
Mr. O
Kennedy B-PERSON
saying O
he O
had O
received O
Senator O
Allen B-PERSON
Ellender I-PERSON
, O
of O
Louisiana B-LOCATION
, O
sparked O
off O
the O
opposition B-NORP
by O
telling O
a O
television O
audience O
it O
was O
" O
current O
Washington B-LOCATION
gossip O
" O
that O
Weaver B-PERSON
once O
had O
Communist B-NORP
affilia- O
tions O
. O

The O
Senate B-ORGANIZATION
Banking I-ORGANIZATION
Committee I-ORGANIZATION
, O
which O
is O
headed O
by O
another O
Southern B-NORP
Senator O
- O
Willis B-PERSON
Robertson I-PERSON
, O
of O
Virginia B-LOCATION
- O
met O
today B-TIME
in O
closed O
session O
to O
discuss O
Weaver's B-PERSON
appointment O
. O

Senator O
Robertson B-PERSON
later O
disclosed O
he O
had O
sent O
a O
letter O
to O
Mr. O
Kennedy B-PERSON
saying O
he O
had O
received O
several O
complaints O
about O
Weaver's B-PERSON
loyalty O
. O

He O
said O
these O
concerned O
Mr. O
Weaver's B-PERSON
alleged O
association O
with O
organisations O
black- O
listed O
by O
the O
Government B-ORGANIZATION
. O

Immediately O
Mr. O
Kennedy B-PERSON
rushed O
a O
letter O
to O
Senator O
Robertson B-PERSON
saying O
the O
Federal B-ORGANIZATION
Bureau I-ORGANIZATION
of I-ORGANIZATION
In- I-ORGANIZATION
vestigation I-ORGANIZATION
had O
reported O
on O
Mr. O
Weaver B-PERSON
. O

He O
believed O
he O
would O
perform O
" O
outstanding O
service O
" O
in O
his O
post O
. O

Senator O
Robertson's B-PERSON
committee O
has O
to O
pass O
Mr. O
Weaver's B-PERSON
nomination O
before O
it O
can O
be O
con- O
 O
sidered O
by O
the O
full O
Senate B-ORGANIZATION
. O

He O
said O
these O
concerned O
Mr. O
Weaver's B-PERSON
alleged O
association O
with O
organisations O
black- O
listed O
by O
the O
Government B-ORGANIZATION
. O

Immediately O
Mr. O
Kennedy B-PERSON
rushed O
a O
letter O
to O
Senator O
Robertson B-PERSON
saying O
the O
Federal B-ORGANIZATION
Bureau I-ORGANIZATION
of I-ORGANIZATION
Investigation I-ORGANIZATION
had O
reported O
on O
Mr. O
Weaver B-PERSON
. O

He O
believed O
he O
would O
perform O
" O
outstanding O
service O
" O
in O
his O
post O
. O

Senator O
Robertson's B-PERSON
committee O
has O
to O
pass O
Mr. O
Weaver's B-PERSON
nomination O
before O
it O
can O
be O
considered O
by O
the O
full O
Senate B-ORGANIZATION
. O

He O
said O
these O
concerned O
Mr. O
Weaver's B-PERSON
alleged O
association O
with O
organisations O
black-listed O
by O
the O
Government B-ORGANIZATION
. O

Immediately O
Mr. O
Kennedy B-PERSON
rushed O
a O
letter O
to O
Senator O
Robertson B-PERSON
saying O
the O
Federal B-ORGANIZATION
Bureau I-ORGANIZATION
of I-ORGANIZATION
Investigation I-ORGANIZATION
had O
reported O
on O
Mr. O
Weaver B-PERSON
. O

He O
believed O
he O
would O
perform O
" O
outstanding O
service O
" O
in O
his O
post O
. O

Senator O
Robertson's B-PERSON
committee O
has O
to O
pass O
Mr. O
Weaver's B-PERSON
nomination O
before O
it O
can O
be O
considered O
by O
the O
full O
Senate B-ORGANIZATION
. O

PRESIDENT O
KENNEDY B-PERSON
is O
ready O
to O
get O
tough O
over O
West B-LOCATION
Germany's I-LOCATION
cash O
offer O
to O
help O
America's B-LOCATION
balance O
of O
payments O
position O
. O

He O
said O
bluntly O
in O
Washington B-LOCATION
yester- B-TIME
day I-TIME
that O
the O
offer O
- O
357million B-CARDINAL
- O
was O
not O
good O
enough O
. O

And O
he O
indicated O
that O
his O
Government B-ORGANIZATION
would O
try O
to O
get O
Germany B-LOCATION
to O
pay O
more O
. O

He O
did O
not O
mention O
personal O
talks O
with O
Dr. O
Adenauer B-PERSON
, O
the O
West B-NORP
German I-NORP
Chancellor O
. O

PRESIDENT O
KENNEDY B-PERSON
is O
ready O
to O
get O
tough O
over O
West B-LOCATION
Germany's I-LOCATION
cash O
offer O
to O
help O
America's B-LOCATION
balance O
of O
payments O
position O
. O

He O
said O
bluntly O
in O
Washington B-LOCATION
yesterday B-TIME
that O
the O
offer O
- O
357million B-CARDINAL
- O
was O
not O
good O
enough O
. O

And O
he O
indicated O
that O
his O
Government B-ORGANIZATION
would O
try O
to O
get O
Germany B-LOCATION
to O
pay O
more O
. O

He O
did O
not O
mention O
personal O
talks O
with O
Dr. O
Adenauer B-PERSON
, O
the O
West B-NORP
German I-NORP
Chancellor O
. O

PRESIDENT O
KENNEDY B-PERSON
is O
ready O
to O
get O
tough O
over O
West B-LOCATION
Germany's I-LOCATION
cash O
offer O
to O
help O
America's B-LOCATION
balance O
of O
payments O
position O
He O
said O
bluntly O
in O
Washington B-LOCATION
yesterday B-TIME
that O
the O
offer O
- O
357million B-CARDINAL
- O
was O
not O
good O
enough O
. O

And O
he O
indicated O
that O
his O
Government B-ORGANIZATION
would O
try O
to O
get O
Germany B-LOCATION
to O
pay O
more O
. O

He O
did O
not O
mention O
personal O
talks O
with O
Dr. O
Adenauer B-PERSON
, O
the O
West B-NORP
German I-NORP
Chancellor O
. O

But O
he O
said O
discussions O
" O
on O
a O
higher O
level O
than O
in O
the O
past O
" O
might O
be O
useful O
. O

The O
President O
will O
probably O
discuss O
the O
problem O
with O
Dr. O
Brentano B-PERSON
, O
the O
West B-NORP
German I-NORP
Foreign O
Minister O
, O
who O
is O
due O
in O
Washington B-LOCATION
next B-TIME
week I-TIME
. O

A O
big O
slice O
of O
Germany's B-LOCATION
" O
aid O
" O
 O
is O
the O
early O
payment O
of O
a O
210million B-CARDINAL
debt O
to O
America B-LOCATION
. O

United B-LOCATION
States I-LOCATION
officials O
quickly O
point O
out O
that O
this O
is O
money O
due O
to O
America B-LOCATION
anyway O
. O

But O
he O
said O
discussions O
" O
on O
a O
higher O
level O
than O
in O
the O
past O
" O
might O
be O
useful O
. O

The O
President O
will O
probably O
discuss O
the O
problem O
with O
Dr. O
Brentano B-PERSON
, O
the O
West B-NORP
German I-NORP
Foreign O
Minister O
, O
who O
is O
due O
in O
Washington B-LOCATION
next B-TIME
week I-TIME
. O

A O
big O
slice O
of O
Germany's B-LOCATION
" O
aid O
" O
is O
the O
early O
payment O
of O
a O
210million B-CARDINAL
debt O
to O
America B-LOCATION
. O

United B-LOCATION
States I-LOCATION
officials O
quickly O
point O
out O
that O
this O
is O
money O
due O
to O
America B-LOCATION
anyway O
. O

But O
he O
said O
discussions O
" O
on O
a O
higher O
level O
than O
in O
the O
past O
" O
might O
be O
useful O
. O

The O
President O
will O
probably O
discuss O
the O
problem O
with O
Dr. O
Brentano B-PERSON
, O
the O
West B-NORP
German I-NORP
Foreign O
Minister O
, O
who O
is O
due O
in O
Washington B-LOCATION
next B-TIME
week I-TIME
. O

A O
big O
slice O
of O
Germany's B-LOCATION
" O
aid O
" O
is O
the O
early O
payment O
of O
a O
210million B-CARDINAL
debt O
to O
America B-LOCATION
. O

United B-LOCATION
States I-LOCATION
officials O
quickly O
point O
out O
that O
this O
is O
money O
due O
to O
America B-LOCATION
anyway O
. O

And O
they O
are O
unimpressed O
by O
the O
Germans' B-NORP
claim O
that O
they O
cannot O
pay O
more B-CARDINAL
than I-CARDINAL
357million I-CARDINAL
without O
upsetting O
their O
own O
economy O
. O

The O
Americans B-NORP
say O
Germany B-LOCATION
is O
having O
it O
too O
good O
and O
is O
not O
paying O
for O
the O
past O
or O
for O
the O
present O
. O

The O
Adenauer B-ORGANIZATION
Government I-ORGANIZATION
flatly O
rejected O
attempts O
by O
the O
Eisenhower B-ORGANIZATION
Government I-ORGANIZATION
to O
get O
them O
to O
pay O
a O
regular O
sum O
towards O
the O
cost O
of O
keeping O
American B-NORP
troops O
in O
Germany B-LOCATION
. O

These O
support O
costs O
are O
a O
big O
drain O
on O
America's B-LOCATION
dollar O
reserves O
. O

Dr. O
Adenauer's B-PERSON
answer O
is O
the O
once-and-for-all O
cash O
offer O
of O
357million B-CARDINAL
. O

President O
Kennedy's B-PERSON
rejection O
of O
it O
is O
a O
painful O
blow O
to O
the O
West B-ORGANIZATION
German I-ORGANIZATION
Government I-ORGANIZATION
. O

It O
will O
now O
have O
to O
pay O
more O
- O
and O
increase O
taxation O
to O
do O
so O
- O
or O
run O
the O
obvious O
 O
risks O
in O
upsetting O
the O
new O
American B-NORP
administration O
. O

These O
support O
costs O
are O
a O
big O
drain O
on O
America's B-LOCATION
dollar O
reserves O
. O

Dr. O
Adenauer's B-PERSON
answer O
is O
the O
once-and-for-all O
cash O
offer O
of O
357million B-CARDINAL
. O

President O
Kennedy's B-PERSON
rejection O
of O
it O
is O
a O
painful O
blow O
to O
the O
West B-ORGANIZATION
German I-ORGANIZATION
Government I-ORGANIZATION
. O

It O
will O
now O
have O
to O
pay O
more O
- O
and O
increase O
taxation O
to O
do O
so O
- O
or O
run O
the O
obvious O
risks O
in O
upsetting O
the O
new O
American B-NORP
administration O
. O

And O
, O
since O
this O
is O
election O
year O
in O
West B-LOCATION
Germany I-LOCATION
, O
Dr. O
Adenauer B-PERSON
is O
in O
a O
tough O
spot O
. O

Joyce B-PERSON
Egginton I-PERSON
cables O
: O
President O
Kennedy B-PERSON
at O
his O
Washington B-LOCATION
Press O
con- O
ference O
admitted O
he O
did O
not O
know O
whether O
America B-LOCATION
was O
lagging O
behind O
Russia B-LOCATION
in O
missile O
power O
. O

He O
said O
he O
was O
waiting O
for O
his O
senior O
military O
aides O
to O
come O
up O
with O
the O
answer O
on O
February B-TIME
20 I-TIME
. O

And O
, O
since O
this O
is O
election O
year O
in O
West B-LOCATION
Germany I-LOCATION
, O
Dr. O
Adenauer B-PERSON
is O
in O
a O
tough O
spot O
. O

Joyce B-PERSON
Egginton I-PERSON
cables O
: O
President O
Kennedy B-PERSON
at O
his O
Washington B-LOCATION
Press O
conference O
admitted O
he O
did O
not O
know O
whether O
America B-LOCATION
was O
lagging O
behind O
Russia B-LOCATION
in O
missile O
power O
. O

He O
said O
he O
was O
waiting O
for O
his O
senior O
military O
aides O
to O
come O
up O
with O
the O
answer O
on O
February B-TIME
20 I-TIME
. O

This O
surprising O
statement O
was O
a O
sharp O
about- O
face O
from O
his O
warnings O
during O
the O
Presidential O
election O
campaign O
. O

He O
claimed O
slackness O
in O
the O
Eisenhower B-ORGANIZATION
Administration I-ORGANIZATION
had O
caused O
America B-LOCATION
to O
lag O
behind O
Russia B-LOCATION
in O
nuclear O
development O
. O

President O
Kennedy B-PERSON
did O
his O
best O
to O
avoid O
giving O
Pressmen O
a O
direct O
answer O
. O

George B-PERSON
Brown I-PERSON
CHILDREN O
TWO B-CARDINAL
men O
who O
are O
poles O
apart O
in O
personality O
last B-TIME
night I-TIME
dominated O
Mr. O
Brown B-PERSON
, O
passionate O
and O
warm-hearted O
, O
led O
Labour's B-ORGANIZATION
attack O
on O
the O
higher O
health O
charges O
. O

Mr. O
Powell B-PERSON
, O
white-faced O
and O
outwardly O
unemotional O
, O
replied O
with O
a O
statistical O
state- O
ment O
- O
and O
ended O
by O
inciting O
Labour B-ORGANIZATION
M Ps O
to O
angry O
uproar O
. O

One B-CARDINAL
dealt O
with O
the O
human O
issue O
behind O
the O
Health B-ORGANIZATION
Service I-ORGANIZATION
; O
the O
other O
tried O
to O
show O
that O
the O
balance-sheet O
must O
always O
come O
first B-CARDINAL
. O

Mr. O
Brown B-PERSON
, O
passionate O
and O
warm-hearted O
, O
led O
Labour's B-ORGANIZATION
attack O
on O
the O
higher O
health O
charges O
. O

Mr. O
Powell B-PERSON
, O
white-faced O
and O
outwardly O
unemotional O
, O
replied O
with O
a O
statistical O
statement O
- O
and O
ended O
by O
inciting O
Labour B-ORGANIZATION
M Ps O
to O
angry O
uproar O
. O

One B-CARDINAL
dealt O
with O
the O
human O
issue O
behind O
the O
Health B-ORGANIZATION
Service I-ORGANIZATION
; O
the O
other O
tried O
to O
show O
that O
the O
balance-sheet O
must O
always O
come O
first B-CARDINAL
. O

The O
result O
of O
the O
vote O
was O
not O
in O
doubt O
. O

For O
the O
Tories B-NORP
were O
massed O
in O
answer O
to O
their O
whips O
to O
defeat O
a O
censure O
motion O
on O
the O
Government B-ORGANIZATION
for O
" O
undermining O
the O
Health B-ORGANIZATION
Service I-ORGANIZATION
" O
and O
placing O
heavy O
burdens O
on O
those O
least O
able O
to O
bear O
them O
. O

Mr. O
Brown B-PERSON
declared O
that O
the O
policy O
under O
censure O
was O
monstrous O
. O

It O
had O
offended O
many O
people O
far O
beyond O
the O
ranks O
of O
Labour B-ORGANIZATION
supporters O
. O

The O
result O
of O
the O
vote O
was O
not O
in O
doubt O
. O

For O
the O
Tories B-NORP
were O
massed O
in O
answer O
to O
their O
whips O
to O
defeat O
a O
censure O
motion O
on O
the O
Government B-ORGANIZATION
for O
" O
undermining O
the O
Health B-ORGANIZATION
Service I-ORGANIZATION
" O
and O
placing O
heavy O
burdens O
on O
those O
least O
able O
to O
bear O
them O
. O

Mr. O
Brown B-PERSON
declared O
that O
the O
policy O
under O
censure O
was O
monstrous O
. O

It O
had O
offended O
many O
people O
far O
beyond O
the O
ranks O
of O
Labour B-ORGANIZATION
supporters O
. O

The O
Press O
, O
many O
doctors O
and O
public O
were O
denouncing O
the O
proposals O
. O

He O
quoted O
from O
this O
letter O
which O
Mr. O
Gaitskell B-PERSON
had O
received O
: O
" O
My O
background O
is O
a O
doctor O
of O
68 B-CARDINAL
, O
who O
has O
practised O
medicine O
for O
43 B-TIME
years I-TIME
, O
chiefly O
as O
a O
panel O
doctor O
. O

" O
I O
am O
a O
lifelong O
Conservative B-ORGANIZATION
. O

I O
am O
horrified O
and O
amazed O
by O
my O
party's O
proposal O
to O
prostitute O
the O
whole O
principle O
of O
the O
State B-ORGANIZATION
service O
and O
to O
render O
that O
service O
a O
hardship O
to O
poor O
people O
. O

" O
After O
a O
lifetime O
of O
helping O
others O
and O
healing O
the O
sick O
, O
my O
considered O
opinion O
is O
that O
anybody O
supporting O
the O
increased O
charges O
is O
a O
wicked O
, O
old O
- O
. O

" O
Mr. O
Brown B-PERSON
went O
on O
: O
" O
We O
are O
dealing O
with O
a O
noble O
edifice O
which O
needs O
an O
imaginative O
architect O
to O
improve O
it O
, O
but O
it O
has O
got O
a O
quantity O
surveyor O
. O

We O
have O
descended O
from O
the O
real O
problems O
to O
fiddling O
about O
with O
bills O
of O
cost O
. O

" O
After O
a O
lifetime O
of O
helping O
others O
and O
healing O
the O
sick O
, O
my O
considered O
opinion O
is O
that O
anybody O
supporting O
the O
increased O
charges O
is O
a O
wicked O
, O
old O
- O
. O

" O
Mr. O
Brown B-PERSON
went O
on O
: O
" O
We O
are O
dealing O
with O
a O
noble O
edifice O
which O
needs O
an O
imaginative O
architect O
to O
improve O
it O
, O
but O
it O
has O
got O
a O
quantity O
surveyor O
. O

We O
have O
descended O
from O
the O
real O
problems O
to O
fiddling O
about O
with O
bills O
of O
cost O
. O

We O
believe O
that O
a O
comprehensive O
medical O
service O
, O
free O
to O
the O
patient O
at O
the O
point O
of O
need O
and O
with O
one B-CARDINAL
standard O
for O
all O
sick O
people O
, O
is O
good O
and O
attainable O
. O

" O
We O
remain O
for O
it O
. O

But O
the O
Tories B-NORP
never O
were O
. O

" O
Interrupted O
by O
angry O
Tories B-NORP
, O
Mr. O
Brown B-PERSON
retorted O
: O
" O
The O
jackals O
bay O
when O
there O
is O
nothing O
better O
they O
can O
do O
. O

" O
" O
We O
believe O
that O
a O
comprehensive O
medical O
service O
, O
free O
to O
the O
patient O
at O
the O
point O
of O
need O
and O
with O
one B-CARDINAL
standard O
for O
all O
sick O
people O
, O
is O
good O
and O
attainable O
. O

" O
We O
remain O
for O
it O
. O

But O
the O
Tories B-NORP
never O
were O
. O

" O
Interrupted O
by O
angry O
Tories B-NORP
, O
Mr. O
Brown B-PERSON
retorted O
: O
" O
The O
jackals O
bay O
when O
there O
is O
nothing O
better O
they O
can O
do O
. O

" O
He O
told O
them O
that O
their O
conception O
of O
social O
services O
was O
wholly O
different O
- O
fundamentally O
different O
from O
that O
of O
Labour B-ORGANIZATION
. O

They O
would O
provide O
an O
ambulance O
service O
for O
the O
absolutely O
wretched O
- O
but O
it O
would O
not O
be O
too O
comfortable O
nor O
too O
easy O
to O
get O
. O

Answering O
jeers O
that O
it O
was O
Labour B-ORGANIZATION
which O
first B-CARDINAL
put O
a O
ceiling O
on O
health O
spending O
and O
started O
charges O
, O
Mr. O
Brown B-PERSON
reminded O
the O
hostile O
Government B-ORGANIZATION
benches O
that O
was O
done O
in O
1950 B-TIME
because O
of O
the O
financial O
strain O
of O
the O
Korean B-NORP
war O
. O

He O
told O
them O
that O
their O
conception O
of O
social O
services O
was O
wholly O
different O
- O
fundamentally O
different O
from O
that O
of O
Labour B-ORGANIZATION
. O

They O
would O
provide O
an O
ambulance O
service O
for O
the O
absolutely O
wretched O
- O
but O
it O
would O
not O
be O
too O
comfortable O
nor O
too O
easy O
to O
get O
. O

Answering O
jeers O
that O
it O
was O
Labour B-ORGANIZATION
which O
first B-CARDINAL
put O
a O
ceiling O
on O
health O
spending O
and O
started O
charges O
, O
Mr. O
Brown B-ORGANIZATION
reminded O
the O
hostile O
Government B-ORGANIZATION
benches O
that O
was O
done O
in O
1950 B-TIME
because O
of O
the O
financial O
strain O
of O
the O
Korean B-NORP
war O
. O

In O
fact O
, O
the O
Tories B-NORP
made O
it O
worse O
now O
for O
the O
sick O
and O
needy O
than O
Labour B-ORGANIZATION
had O
to O
make O
it O
in O
1950 B-TIME
. O

And O
as O
a O
percentage O
of O
social O
service O
expenditure O
, O
health O
had O
fallen O
from O
28.5 B-CARDINAL
to O
23.1 B-CARDINAL
per O
cent. O
Then O
Mr. O
Brown B-PERSON
swung O
his O
attack O
directly O
to O
the O
unsmiling O
Mr. O
Powell B-PERSON
. O

He O
demanded O
that O
instead O
of O
taking O
it O
out O
of O
the O
patients O
Mr. O
Powell B-PERSON
should O
take O
ruthless O
action O
against O
the O
drug O
making O
industry O
, O
whose O
profits O
had O
risen O
by O
up B-CARDINAL
to I-CARDINAL
400 I-CARDINAL
per O
cent. O
in O
the B-TIME
last I-TIME
eight I-TIME
years I-TIME
. O

In O
fact O
, O
the O
Tories B-NORP
made O
it O
worse O
now O
for O
the O
sick O
and O
needy O
than O
Labour B-ORGANIZATION
had O
to O
make O
it O
in O
1950 B-TIME
. O

And O
as O
a O
percentage O
of O
social O
service O
expenditure O
, O
health O
had O
fallen O
from O
28.5 B-CARDINAL
to O
23.1 B-CARDINAL
per O
cent. O
Then O
Mr. O
Brown B-PERSON
swung O
his O
attack O
directly O
to O
the O
unsmiling O
Mr. O
Powell B-PERSON
. O

He O
demanded O
that O
instead O
of O
taking O
it O
out O
of O
the O
patients O
Mr. O
Powell B-PERSON
should O
take O
ruthless O
action O
against O
the O
drug O
making O
industry O
, O
 O
whose O
profits O
had O
risen O
by O
up B-CARDINAL
to I-CARDINAL
400 I-CARDINAL
per O
" O
Mr. O
Powell B-PERSON
finds O
it O
easier O
to O
take O
it O
out O
of O
mothers O
, O
children O
and O
sick O
people O
than O
to O
take O
on O
this O
vast O
industry O
, O
" O
Mr. O
Brown B-PERSON
commented O
icily O
. O

" O
Let O
us O
have O
a O
full O
inquiry O
into O
the O
cost O
of O
drugs O
and O
the O
pharmaceutical O
industry O
. O

" O
The O
health O
of O
children O
today B-TIME
owed O
much O
to O
the O
welfare O
food O
scheme O
. O

It O
was O
maintained O
during O
the O
war O
. O

Now O
in O
conditions O
of O
Tory B-ORGANIZATION
affluence O
it O
seemed O
it O
could O
not O
be O
carried O
on O
. O

" O
Mr. O
Powell B-PERSON
finds O
it O
easier O
to O
take O
it O
out O
of O
mothers O
, O
children O
and O
sick O
people O
than O
to O
take O
on O
this O
vast O
industry O
, O
" O
Mr. O
Brown B-PERSON
commented O
icily O
. O

" O
Let O
us O
have O
a O
full O
inquiry O
into O
the O
cost O
of O
drugs O
and O
the O
pharmaceutical O
industry O
. O

" O
The O
health O
of O
children O
today B-TIME
owed O
much O
to O
the O
welfare O
food O
scheme O
. O

It O
was O
maintained O
during O
the O
war O
. O

Now O
in O
conditions O
of O
Tory B-ORGANIZATION
affluence O
it O
seemed O
it O
could O
not O
be O
carried O
on O
. O

When O
Mr. O
Brown B-PERSON
sat O
down O
Labour B-ORGANIZATION
M Ps O
cheered O
for O
a B-TIME
full I-TIME
minute I-TIME
- O
and O
even O
his O
bitterest O
opponents O
on O
defence O
joined O
in O
. O

Mr. O
Powell B-PERSON
devoted O
half B-CARDINAL
his O
speech O
to O
giving O
details O
of O
plans O
for O
improving O
the O
hospital O
service O
, O
on O
which O
indeed O
the O
Government B-ORGANIZATION
is O
making O
progress O
. O

His O
basic O
defence O
of O
the O
Health B-ORGANIZATION
Service I-ORGANIZATION
cuts O
was O
that O
" O
even O
after O
the O
proposed O
changes O
the O
net O
cost O
of O
the O
service O
to O
the O
Exchequer B-ORGANIZATION
will O
have O
increased O
over O
three B-TIME
years I-TIME
by O
20 B-CARDINAL
per O
cent. O
When O
Mr. O
Brown B-PERSON
sat O
down O
Labour B-ORGANIZATION
M Ps O
cheered O
for O
a B-TIME
full I-TIME
minute I-TIME
- O
and O
even O
his O
bitterest O
opponents O
on O
defence O
joined O
in O
. O

Mr. O
Powell B-PERSON
devoted O
half B-CARDINAL
his O
speech O
to O
giving O
details O
of O
plans O
for O
improving O
the O
hospital O
service O
, O
on O
which O
indeed O
the O
Government B-ORGANIZATION
is O
making O
progress O
. O

His O
basic O
defence O
of O
the O
Health B-ORGANIZATION
Service I-ORGANIZATION
cuts O
was O
that O
" O
even O
after O
the O
proposed O
changes O
the O
net O
cost O
of O
the O
service O
to O
the O
Exchequer B-ORGANIZATION
will O
have O
increased O
over O
three B-TIME
years I-TIME
by O
20 B-CARDINAL
per O
cent. O
" O
That O
cannot O
continue O
without O
either O
development O
being O
limited O
or O
an O
adjustment O
being O
made O
in O
financing O
. O

" O
The O
Government B-ORGANIZATION
decided O
to O
adjust O
the O
financing O
- O
which O
Mr. O
Powell B-PERSON
claimed O
was O
underpinning O
- O
not O
undermining O
- O
the O
service O
. O

Answering O
the O
attack O
on O
" O
economic O
charges O
" O
for O
welfare O
foods O
, O
Mr. O
Powell B-PERSON
said O
that O
all O
these O
foods O
would O
still O
be O
free O
in O
families O
receiving O
regular O
National O
Assistance O
grants O
. O

" O
That O
cannot O
continue O
without O
either O
development O
being O
limited O
or O
an O
adjustment O
being O
made O
in O
financing O
. O

" O
The O
Government B-ORGANIZATION
decided O
to O
adjust O
the O
financing O
- O
which O
Mr. O
Powell B-PERSON
claimed O
was O
underpinning O
- O
not O
undermining O
- O
the O
service O
. O

Answering O
the O
attack O
on O
" O
economic O
charges O
" O
for O
welfare O
foods O
, O
Mr. O
Powell B-PERSON
said O
that O
all O
these O
foods O
would O
still O
be O
free O
in O
families O
receiving O
regular O
National O
Assistance O
grants O
. O

" O
That O
cannot O
continue O
without O
either O
development O
being O
limited O
or O
an O
adjustment O
being O
made O
in O
financing O
. O

" O
The O
Government B-ORGANIZATION
decided O
to O
adjust O
the O
financing O
- O
which O
Mr. O
Powell B-PERSON
claimed O
was O
underpinning O
- O
not O
undermining O
- O
the O
service O
. O

Answering O
the O
attack O
on O
" O
economic O
charges O
" O
for O
welfare O
, O
Mr. O
Powell B-PERSON
said O
that O
all O
these O
foods O
would O
still O
be O
free O
in O
families O
receiving O
regular O
National O
Assistance O
grants O
. O

In O
some O
ways O
it O
will O
be O
a O
testing O
occasion O
for O
him O
, O
although O
some O
think O
his O
position O
unassailable O
simply O
because O
there O
is O
no O
one O
else O
in O
sight O
to O
supplant O
him O
. O

So O
the O
con- O
ference O
will O
concentrate O
on O
laying O
the O
foundations O
on O
which O
to O
win O
the O
next O
election O
. O

The O
rally O
comes O
at O
a O
time O
when O
in O
spite O
of O
carefully O
worded O
state- O
ments O
by O
the O
Prime O
Minister O
there O
is O
an O
air O
of O
electoral O
expectancy O
. O

On O
the O
other O
hand O
, O
Mr. O
Pearson B-PERSON
excels O
in O
meeting O
people O
informally O
, O
but O
many O
still O
regard O
him O
" O
as O
some O
sort O
of O
cross O
between O
an O
egghead O
and O
a O
missionary O
" O
. O

His O
party O
advisers O
are O
now O
trying O
to O
correct O
that O
image O
. O

The O
bow O
tie O
has O
gone O
; O
he O
is O
having O
lessons O
on O
television O
techniques O
and O
is O
being O
coached O
by O
speech O
experts O
. O

Mr. O
Thorneycroft's B-PERSON
main O
purpose O
will O
be O
to O
remove O
these O
doubts O
, O
and O
to O
persuade O
the O
Federal B-ORGANIZATION
Government I-ORGANIZATION
that O
the O
financial O
burden O
involved O
is O
really O
worth O
while O
, O
at O
a O
time O
when O
any O
increase O
in O
budgetary O
commitments O
would O
almost O
certainly O
involve O
a O
corresponding O
rise O
in O
taxation O
- O
something O
no O
one O
is O
prepared O
to O
contemplate O
in O
an B-TIME
election I-TIME
year I-TIME
. O

But O
, O
at O
the O
same O
time O
, O
there O
is O
reason O
to O
believe O
that O
the O
Federal B-ORGANIZATION
Government I-ORGANIZATION
is O
not O
convinced O
, O
on O
the O
basis O
of O
the O
information O
it O
has O
so O
far O
, O
that O
such O
a O
project O
would O
be O
justified O
from O
a O
scientific O
point O
of O
view O
; O
and O
not O
merely O
constitute O
a O
" O
prestige O
" O
satellite O
, O
duplicating O
to O
some O
extent O
American B-NORP
efforts O
, O
as O
Die B-ORGANIZATION
Welt I-ORGANIZATION
suggests O
today B-TIME
in O
a O
highly O
critical O
editorial O
article O
. O

On O
the O
specific O
question O
of O
the O
use O
of O
Blue O
Streak O
, O
Mr. O
Thorneycroft's B-PERSON
task O
will O
be O
easier O
. O

He O
can O
point O
out O
that O
this O
is O
the O
only O
rocket O
and O
launcher O
in O
Europe B-LOCATION
to O
have O
reached O
a O
sufficient O
stage O
of O
development O
for O
adaptation O
as O
the O
first B-CARDINAL
stage O
in O
putting O
a O
heavy O
satellite O
into O
outer O
space O
. O

There O
has O
also O
been O
some O
talk O
of O
adopting O
another O
British B-NORP
rocket O
, O
Black O
Knight O
, O
for O
the O
second B-CARDINAL
stage O
, O
but O
the O
French B-NORP
have O
one O
of O
their O
own O
called O
Veronique O
which O
they O
would O
like O
to O
see O
used O
. O

The O
Foreign B-ORGANIZATION
Ministry I-ORGANIZATION
spokesman O
added O
today B-TIME
, O
however O
, O
that O
the O
Brussels B-LOCATION
Treaty O
was O
irrelevant O
, O
because O
research O
on O
the O
various O
rocket O
stages O
had O
already O
been O
concluded O
, O
and O
only O
cooperation O
on O
the O
type O
of O
capsule O
was O
involved O
. O

A O
lesser O
obstacle O
to O
German B-NORP
participation O
is O
the O
absence O
of O
any O
Ministry B-ORGANIZATION
or O
Minister O
directly O
responsible O
for O
it O
- O
and O
therefore O
of O
any O
budget O
under O
which O
funds O
could O
be O
appropriated O
. O

This O
is O
expected O
eventually O
to O
replace O
the O
Fiat B-ORGANIZATION
G-91 O
, O
and O
the O
F O
104 O
Starfighter O
, O
the O
backbone O
of O
the O
German B-ORGANIZATION
Air I-ORGANIZATION
Force I-ORGANIZATION
. O

THE O
next O
White O
Paper O
on O
defence O
, O
to O
be O
published O
in O
March B-TIME
, O
is O
likely O
to O
contain O
a O
five-year B-TIME
plan O
for O
the O
three B-ORGANIZATION
Services I-ORGANIZATION
. O

Its O
aim O
will O
be O
to O
produce O
superbly O
equipped O
, O
all-Regular O
forces O
of O
about B-CARDINAL
400,000 I-CARDINAL
men O
. O

The O
three B-ORGANIZATION
Services I-ORGANIZATION
would O
be O
" O
integrated O
" O
to O
a O
greater O
extent O
than O
ever O
before O
. O

The O
scheme O
will O
be O
subject O
to O
Cabinet B-ORGANIZATION
approval O
. O

Mr. O
Watkinson B-PERSON
remains O
con- O
vinced O
that O
the O
policy O
initiated O
in O
1957 B-TIME
, O
in O
Mr. O
Sandys's B-PERSON
time O
as O
Minister O
of O
Defence O
, O
is O
still O
correct O
. O

This O
was O
to O
return O
to O
the O
tradition O
of O
all-Regular O
voluntary O
forces O
, O
with O
the O
last O
National O
Serviceman O
out O
of O
uniform O
by O
the B-TIME
end I-TIME
of I-TIME
1962 I-TIME
. O

The O
Minister O
regards O
the O
recent O
trend O
of O
recruiting O
figures O
as O
encouraging O
. O

He O
is O
confident O
the O
aim O
can O
be O
achieved O
. O

While O
the O
possibility O
of O
an O
eventual O
return O
to O
National O
Service O
in O
some O
form O
cannot O
be O
entirely O
discounted O
, O
he O
does O
not O
agree O
that O
the O
point O
has O
been O
reached O
where O
this O
need O
even O
be O
considered O
. O

If O
National O
Service O
is O
ever O
resorted O
to O
, O
engagement O
would O
probably O
have O
to O
be O
for O
three B-TIME
years I-TIME
. O

It O
is O
thought O
this O
would O
be O
the O
minimum O
necessary O
for O
the O
extended O
training O
modern O
arms O
require O
and O
to O
enable O
each O
man O
to O
serve O
at B-TIME
least I-TIME
a I-TIME
year I-TIME
overseas O
. O

There O
is O
no O
truth O
in O
suggestions O
that O
Mr. O
Watkinson B-PERSON
is O
at O
odds O
with O
the O
Service B-ORGANIZATION
chiefs O
over O
the O
decision O
to O
dispense O
with O
National O
Service O
, O
or O
over O
any O
other O
aspect O
of O
defence O
policy O
. O

Criticisms O
about O
Army B-ORGANIZATION
manpower O
appear O
to O
have O
come O
mainly O
from O
retired O
officers O
who O
have O
held O
high O
positions O
but O
are O
out O
of O
touch O
with O
the O
existing O
situation O
. O

Mr. O
Watkinson B-PERSON
has O
had O
the O
utmost O
support O
from O
the O
C.I.G.S. B-ORGANIZATION
, O
Field-Marshal O
Sir O
Francis B-PERSON
Festing I-PERSON
, O
who O
believes O
completely O
in O
the O
principle O
of O
an O
all-Regular O
army O
. O

Gen. O
Sir O
Richard B-PERSON
Hull I-PERSON
, O
who O
is O
to O
succeed O
Sir O
Francis B-PERSON
, O
is O
equally O
convinced O
Mr. O
Watkinson B-PERSON
is O
right O
. O

Sir O
Francis B-PERSON
is O
to O
hand O
over O
to O
Sir O
Richard B-PERSON
as O
from O
Nov. B-TIME
1 I-TIME
. O

The O
hand-over O
, O
due O
in O
September B-TIME
, O
was O
delayed O
because O
of O
the O
Berlin B-LOCATION
crisis O
. O

Mr. O
Watkinson B-PERSON
and O
his O
advisers O
felt O
the O
change O
would O
be O
unwise O
at O
a O
moment O
 O
when O
attention O
had O
to O
be O
concentrated O
on O
possible O
need O
for O
important O
military O
operations O
. O

For O
this O
reason O
Sir O
Francis B-PERSON
stayed O
on O
, O
and O
 O
sacrificed O
his O
leave O
. O

There O
was O
a O
computed O
8.4 B-CARDINAL
per O
cent. O
swing O
towards O
the O
Nationalist B-ORGANIZATION
party I-ORGANIZATION
of O
Dr. O
Verwoerd B-PERSON
, O
the O
Prime O
Minister O
. O

This O
implies O
the O
dis- O
appearance O
of O
the O
Progressive B-ORGANIZATION
party I-ORGANIZATION
from O
the O
House B-ORGANIZATION
. O

Early O
results O
in O
yesterday's B-TIME
general O
election O
showed O
Nationalists B-NORP
being O
returned O
in O
their O
strongholds O
, O
like O
Bloem- B-LOCATION
fontein I-LOCATION
and O
the O
Transvaal B-LOCATION
, O
with O
slightly O
increased O
majorities O
. O

In O
the O
Cape B-LOCATION
, O
the O
veteran O
United B-ORGANIZATION
Party I-ORGANIZATION
politician O
, O
Mr. O
Harry B-PERSON
Lawrence I-PERSON
, O
standing O
as O
a O
Progressive B-NORP
, O
was O
The O
defeat O
of O
the O
leader O
of O
the O
Progressive B-ORGANIZATION
party I-ORGANIZATION
, O
Dr. O
Steytler B-PERSON
, O
in O
Port B-LOCATION
Elizabeth I-LOCATION
South I-LOCATION
, O
announced O
immediately O
afterwards O
by O
the O
United B-ORGANIZATION
party I-ORGANIZATION
candidate O
, O
Mr. O
Plewman B-PERSON
, O
left O
the O
Progressives B-NORP
deprived O
of O
both O
their O
chief O
figures O
. O

Dr. O
Verwoerd B-PERSON
and O
the O
Leader O
of O
the O
Opposition B-ORGANIZATION
, O
Sir O
de B-PERSON
Villiers I-PERSON
Graaff I-PERSON
, O
have O
been O
returned O
unopposed O
. O

The O
contests O
were O
for O
86 B-CARDINAL
seats O
as O
70 B-CARDINAL
Nationalists B-NORP
and O
20 B-CARDINAL
United B-ORGANIZATION
party I-ORGANIZATION
candi- O
dates O
are O
unopposed O
. O

Long O
before O
polling O
closed O
at O
8 B-TIME
p.m. I-TIME
it O
was O
evident O
that O
voters O
were O
bored O
by O
the O
Government's B-ORGANIZATION
frequent O
appeals O
to O
the O
electorate O
. O

The O
election O
was O
the O
fourth B-CARDINAL
in O
four B-TIME
years I-TIME
. O

In O
most O
constituencies O
it O
may O
go O
down O
as O
the O
most O
apathetic O
in O
the O
country's O
history O
. O

THE O
Prime O
Minister O
disclosed O
in O
the O
Commons B-ORGANIZATION
last B-TIME
night I-TIME
that O
he O
had O
considered O
early O
in O
the O
Parliamentary B-ORGANIZATION
recess O
whether O
to O
mobilise O
reserves O
necessary O
to O
bring O
the O
British B-ORGANIZATION
Army I-ORGANIZATION
of I-ORGANIZATION
the I-ORGANIZATION
Rhine I-ORGANIZATION
on O
to O
a O
war O
footing O
. O

He O
decided O
that O
it O
would O
be O
a O
great O
error O
to O
do O
so O
and O
to O
recall O
Parliament B-ORGANIZATION
. O

But O
there O
would O
be O
no O
hesitation O
in O
mobilising O
if O
a O
further O
deterioration O
in O
the O
situation O
warranted O
such O
a O
step O
. O

It O
would O
have O
to O
be O
accompanied O
by O
other O
measures O
of O
a O
military O
, O
economic O
and O
political O
kind O
. O

Mr. O
Macmillan B-PERSON
, O
who O
was O
winding O
up O
the O
foreign O
affairs O
debate O
, O
said O
the O
Government B-ORGANIZATION
could O
not O
be O
party O
to O
accepting O
as O
a O
matter O
of O
principle O
the O
imposed O
division O
of O
Germany B-LOCATION
. O

" O
We O
must O
not O
be O
rattled O
into O
surrender O
, O
but O
we O
must O
not O
- O
and O
I O
am O
not O
- O
be O
afraid O
of O
negotiation O
. O

" O
Mr. O
Godber B-PERSON
, O
Minister O
of O
State O
, O
Foreign B-ORGANIZATION
Office I-ORGANIZATION
, O
said O
earlier O
that O
the O
Government B-ORGANIZATION
had O
asked O
the O
Medical B-ORGANIZATION
Research I-ORGANIZATION
Council I-ORGANIZATION
to O
reassess O
the O
fall-out O
position O
in O
view O
of O
the O
Russian B-NORP
tests O
. O

The O
Council's B-ORGANIZATION
findings O
would O
be O
made O
public O
. O

With O
a O
vigour O
and O
authority O
which O
delighted O
old O
Parliamentary B-ORGANIZATION
friends O
and O
foes O
alike O
, O
the O
Earl O
of O
Avon B-LOCATION
, O
the O
former O
Sir O
Anthony B-PERSON
Eden I-PERSON
, O
in O
his O
maiden O
speech O
in O
the O
House B-ORGANIZATION
of I-ORGANIZATION
Lords I-ORGANIZATION
last B-TIME
night I-TIME
, O
gave O
a O
warning O
that O
 O
appeasement O
over O
Berlin B-LOCATION
could O
only O
lead O
to O
war O
. O

To O
stand O
firm O
, O
he O
declared O
, O
was O
not O
to O
invite O
war O
, O
but O
the O
surest O
way O
to O
avert O
it O
. O

It O
was O
the O
end O
of O
a O
rather O
curious O
speech O
in O
which O
Mr. O
Macmillan B-PERSON
wound O
up O
the O
two-day B-TIME
debate O
on O
foreign O
affairs O
. O

He O
began O
in O
a O
low O
, O
almost O
chatty O
mono- O
tone O
, O
and O
his O
voice O
never O
rose O
to O
any O
accent O
of O
urgency O
. O

He O
passed O
in O
rapid O
review O
the O
United B-ORGANIZATION
Nations I-ORGANIZATION
Secretariat I-ORGANIZATION
; O
nuclear O
tests O
; O
the O
canard O
about O
British B-NORP
interference O
with O
the O
United B-ORGANIZATION
Nations I-ORGANIZATION
in O
the O
Congo B-LOCATION
; O
Kuwait B-LOCATION
; O
and O
South-East B-LOCATION
Asia I-LOCATION
. O

He O
spent O
most O
of O
his O
short O
half-hour B-TIME
on O
Berlin B-LOCATION
. O

He O
deplored O
the O
possibility O
of O
some O
" O
new O
myth O
" O
about O
betrayal O
of O
Germany B-LOCATION
by O
the O
Allies B-NORP
. O

" O
We O
do O
not O
, O
" O
he O
said O
, O
" O
really O
know O
what O
the O
Russians B-NORP
want O
. O

" O
But O
he O
was O
certain O
that O
they O
wanted O
to O
establish O
a O
final O
and O
irrevocable O
division O
of O
Germany B-LOCATION
. O

Britain B-LOCATION
could O
not O
be O
a O
party O
to O
an O
imposed O
division O
. O

But O
negotiation O
, O
as O
the O
debate O
had O
shown O
, O
could O
be O
undertaken O
on O
a O
variety O
of O
bases O
. O

Mr. O
Macmillan B-PERSON
explained O
that O
he O
had O
deliber- O
ately O
refrained O
during O
the O
summer B-TIME
from O
recalling O
Parliament B-ORGANIZATION
or O
ordering O
mobilisation O
by O
proclamation O
, O
such O
as O
would O
be O
necessary O
to O
bring O
the O
British B-ORGANIZATION
Army I-ORGANIZATION
of I-ORGANIZATION
the I-ORGANIZATION
Rhine I-ORGANIZATION
on O
to O
a O
fully O
active O
footing O
. O

That O
would O
have O
created O
a O
thoroughly O
unde- O
sirable O
atmosphere O
of O
panic O
. O

He O
thought O
that O
the O
situation O
was O
rather O
more O
hopeful O
. O

The O
Russians B-NORP
now O
realised O
its O
seriousness O
. O

The O
French B-NORP
doubts O
were O
more O
about O
procedure O
than O
about O
substance O
. O

The O
Prime O
Minister's O
attitude O
of O
studied O
calm O
brought O
down O
the O
temperature O
of O
the O
debate O
, O
which O
never O
at O
any O
time O
rose O
to O
fever O
pitch O
, O
to O
a O
remarkable O
degree O
of O
sub-normality O
. O

Throughout O
Mr. O
Macmillan's B-PERSON
speech O
the O
Earl O
of O
Home B-PERSON
, O
Foreign O
Secretary O
, O
was O
listening O
in O
the O
Peers' B-LOCATION
Gallery I-LOCATION
. O

The O
early O
speakers O
in O
the O
debate O
each O
severely O
rated O
the O
speech O
of O
his O
predecessor O
. O

These O
strictures O
were O
all O
too O
well O
justified O
. O

We O
started O
with O
the O
plaintive O
wailings O
of O
Mr. O
Healey B-PERSON
, O
" O
Shadow O
" O
Foreign O
Secretary O
, O
described O
by O
Mr. O
Godber B-PERSON
, O
Minister O
of O
State O
, O
Foreign B-ORGANIZATION
Office I-ORGANIZATION
, O
as O
" O
pedantic O
and O
obscure O
on O
Berlin B-LOCATION
, O
damaging O
and O
obscure O
on O
the O
Congo B-LOCATION
. O

" O
In O
turn O
, O
Mr. O
Godber B-PERSON
was O
censured O
by O
Mr. O
Shinwell B-PERSON
, O
former O
Labour B-ORGANIZATION
Defence O
Minister O
, O
for O
having O
read O
the O
The O
trouble O
about O
such O
debates O
is O
that O
they O
range O
too O
widely O
. O

They O
remind O
one O
of O
the O
Rugby O
match O
in O
" O
Tom B-PERSON
Brown's I-PERSON
Schooldays O
, O
" O
in O
which O
all O
the O
boys O
were O
welcome O
to O
take O
part O
, O
and O
only O
those O
who O
" O
really O
meant O
business O
" O
removed O
their O
jackets O
. O

Not O
many O
metaphorical O
braces O
were O
visible O
in O
the O
early O
stages O
of O
to-night's B-TIME
debate O
. O

Mr. O
Healey B-PERSON
had O
another O
tilt O
at O
the O
Prime O
Minister's O
golf-course O
Press O
conference O
, O
which O
he O
described O
as O
" O
a O
display O
of O
flabby O
and O
A O
reference O
to O
the O
reunification O
of O
Germany B-LOCATION
brought O
a O
bark O
of O
" O
Start O
another O
war O
! O

" O
from O
Mr. O
Ellis B-PERSON
Smith I-PERSON
( O
Lab. B-ORGANIZATION
, O
Stoke B-LOCATION
on I-LOCATION
Trent I-LOCATION
S. I-LOCATION
) O
. O

Then O
Mr. O
Healey B-PERSON
launched O
out O
on O
his O
pet O
theme O
of O
limitation O
of O
armaments O
in O
Europe B-LOCATION
. O

This O
could O
, O
he O
suggested O
, O
be O
linked O
with O
prohibition O
of O
the O
production O
of O
atomic O
weapons O
in O
any O
part O
of O
Europe B-LOCATION
. O

Inspection O
and O
control O
would O
be O
much O
easier O
to O
establish O
in O
these O
territories O
. O

Mr. O
Healey B-PERSON
denounced O
the O
Government B-ORGANIZATION
for O
using O
double O
standards O
. O

Ministers O
had O
rebuked O
the O
unaligned O
nations O
for O
not O
condemning O
the O
new O
Russian B-NORP
tests O
, O
but O
they O
themselves O
had O
no O
condemnation O
for O
events O
in O
Angola B-LOCATION
or O
Algeria B-LOCATION
. O

It O
was O
not O
for O
the O
Government B-ORGANIZATION
, O
said O
Mr. O
Healey B-PERSON
, O
to O
take O
up O
moral O
attitudes O
, O
" O
especially O
when O
the O
temple O
of O
their O
religion O
is O
the O
bingo-parlour O
. O

" O
This O
puzzled O
such O
students O
of O
comparative O
religion O
as O
had O
failed O
to O
detect O
this O
cult O
. O

But O
Mr. O
Healey B-PERSON
had O
a O
partial O
and O
limited O
success O
. O

He O
rallied O
behind O
him O
the O
Left-wing O
opinion O
so O
coolly O
snubbed O
last B-TIME
night I-TIME
by O
his O
leader O
, O
Mr. O
Gaitskell B-PERSON
. O

Mr. O
Godber's B-PERSON
performance O
merited O
all O
the O
mild O
scorn O
heaped O
on O
it O
by O
Mr. O
Shinwell B-PERSON
. O

True O
, O
he O
did O
tell O
the O
House B-ORGANIZATION
that O
the O
Government B-ORGANIZATION
had O
asked O
the O
Medical B-ORGANIZATION
Research I-ORGANIZATION
Council I-ORGANIZATION
to O
reassess O
the O
fall-out O
position O
in O
view O
of O
the O
Russian B-NORP
tests O
, O
and O
said O
that O
the O
council's B-ORGANIZATION
findings O
would O
be O
published O
. O

He O
was O
not O
so O
happy O
in O
his O
defence O
of O
the O
Government's B-ORGANIZATION
failure O
to O
condemn O
France B-LOCATION
for O
her O
nuclear O
tests O
in O
the O
Sahara B-LOCATION
on O
the O
grounds O
that O
they O
were O
only O
little O
ones O
. O

This O
was O
too O
reminiscent O
of O
the O
nursemaid O
and O
her O
illegitimate O
baby O
. O

For O
the O
most O
part O
, O
Mr. O
Godber B-PERSON
muttered O
his O
way O
through O
a O
cliche-ridden O
Foreign B-ORGANIZATION
Office I-ORGANIZATION
brief O
. O

He O
resembles O
the O
elephant O
seal O
, O
an O
 O
otherwise O
endearing O
creature O
whose O
articulation O
is O
limited O
, O
we O
are O
told O
, O
to O
a O
series O
of O
heavy O
sighs O
. O

Sir O
Lynn B-PERSON
Ungoed- I-PERSON
Thomas I-PERSON
, O
M.P. O
for O
Leicester B-LOCATION
N.E. I-LOCATION
, O
a O
former O
Labour B-ORGANIZATION
Solicitor-General O
, O
and O
Mrs. O
Barbara B-PERSON
It O
was O
signed O
by O
60 B-CARDINAL
Labour B-ORGANIZATION
M.P.s O
, O
many O
of O
them O
Left-wing O
 O
sympathisers O
. O

It O
condemned O
" O
the O
pollution O
of O
the O
world's O
atmosphere O
as O
a O
crime O
against O
humanity O
. O

" O
A O
personal O
letter O
of O
protest O
against O
the O
tests O
from O
Canon B-PERSON
Collins I-PERSON
, O
chairman O
of O
the O
Campaign B-ORGANIZATION
for I-ORGANIZATION
Nuclear I-ORGANIZATION
Disarmament I-ORGANIZATION
, O
addressed O
to O
Mr. O
 O
Khruschev B-PERSON
, O
was O
also O
taken O
to O
the O
Russian B-ORGANIZATION
Embassy I-ORGANIZATION
. O

A O
POLITICAL O
CORRESPONDENT O
writes O
: O
Ban-the- O
bomb O
demonstrators O
thronged O
the O
Central B-LOCATION
Lobby I-LOCATION
of O
the O
House B-ORGANIZATION
of I-ORGANIZATION
Commons I-ORGANIZATION
last B-TIME
night I-TIME
and O
formed O
a O
queue O
stretching O
for O
more B-CARDINAL
than I-CARDINAL
200 I-CARDINAL
yards O
outside O
in O
Old B-LOCATION
Palace I-LOCATION
Yard I-LOCATION
. O

About B-CARDINAL
2,000 I-CARDINAL
lobbied O
M.P.s O
and O
harangued O
them O
on O
disarmament O
. O

Most O
MPs O
agreed O
that O
Mr. O
Fell's B-PERSON
attack O
had O
, O
if O
anything O
, O
rallied O
support O
to O
the O
Prime O
Minister O
. O

This O
apparently O
, O
was O
Mr. O
Macmillan's B-PERSON
assessment O
. O

He O
confined O
his O
reply O
to O
the O
observation O
that O
Mr. O
Fell B-PERSON
had O
probably O
" O
maximised O
his O
support O
. O

" O
There O
were O
no O
other O
attacks O
of O
such O
ferocity O
. O

But O
there O
was O
ample O
evidence O
of O
Conservative B-ORGANIZATION
and O
Labour B-ORGANIZATION
opposition O
, O
which O
will O
be O
aired O
in O
the O
debate O
tomorrow B-TIME
and O
on O
Thursday B-TIME
. O

He O
claimed O
that O
, O
unless O
we O
were O
in O
the O
Common B-ORGANIZATION
Market I-ORGANIZATION
, O
we O
should O
not O
be O
able O
to O
play O
any O
part O
in O
 O
determining O
its O
future O
. O

" O
We O
can O
lead O
better O
from O
within O
, O
" O
he O
said O
. O

Mr. O
Macmillan B-PERSON
dealt O
with O
the O
main O
objection O
raised O
by O
Tory B-ORGANIZATION
critics O
. O

Mr. O
Anthony B-PERSON
Fell I-PERSON
, O
who O
created O
a O
scene O
on O
this O
point O
on O
Monday B-TIME
, O
took O
up O
a O
position O
almost O
hidden O
behind O
the O
Serjeant O
at O
Arms' O
chair O
. O

Prime O
Minister O
after O
Prime O
Minister O
speaks O
out O
in O
revulsion O
against O
the O
South B-ORGANIZATION
African I-ORGANIZATION
Government's I-ORGANIZATION
policy O
of O
apartheid O
as O
we O
wait O
for O
the O
curtain O
to O
rise O
on O
the O
Commonwealth B-ORGANIZATION
Conference I-ORGANIZATION
in O
London B-LOCATION
. O

Will O
it O
end O
with O
South B-LOCATION
Africa's I-LOCATION
exclusion O
from O
the O
Commonwealth B-ORGANIZATION
? O

The O
issue O
is O
touch O
and O
go O
. O

There O
is O
a O
possibility O
that O
it O
will O
not O
be O
settled O
at O
this O
conference O
. O

It O
may O
be O
agreed O
to O
wait O
until O
South B-LOCATION
Africa I-LOCATION
actually O
becomes O
a O
Republic O
later O
in O
the O
year O
. O

But O
if O
a O
final O
decision O
is O
to O
be O
faced O
now O
, O
on O
which O
side O
do O
the O
strongest O
arguments O
lie O
? O

THE O
Archbishop O
of O
Capetown B-LOCATION
has O
shown O
that O
the O
matter O
is O
not O
clear-cut O
. O

The O
Archbishop O
has O
long O
been O
a O
courageous O
fighter O
against O
apartheid O
. O

He O
must O
be O
heard O
with O
attention O
. O

On O
purely O
practical O
grounds O
he O
holds O
that O
it O
would O
be O
a O
mistake O
to O
expel O
South B-LOCATION
Africa I-LOCATION
, O
weakening O
the O
whites O
who O
are O
working O
for O
a O
change O
of O
policy O
. O

In O
his O
view O
it O
would O
also O
be O
against O
the O
interests O
of O
the O
Africans B-NORP
. O

A O
CURIOUS O
advertisement O
on O
page O
nine B-CARDINAL
, O
paid O
for O
by O
that O
curious O
body O
Moral B-ORGANIZATION
Re-Armament I-ORGANIZATION
. O

Those O
who O
lend O
their O
names O
to O
this O
kind O
of O
advertisement O
are O
worthy O
people O
, O
a O
little O
innocent O
of O
politics O
, O
perhaps O
, O
or O
carried O
away O
by O
the O
idea O
that O
moral O
regeneration O
would O
solve O
all O
our O
problems O
. O

So O
it O
would O
. O

While O
we O
are O
waiting O
for O
the O
millenium B-TIME
, O
however O
, O
most O
of O
us O
would O
prefer O
to O
put O
our O
hopes O
for O
earthly O
justice O
in O
instruments O
of O
democracy O
, O
such O
as O
trade O
unions O
and O
our O
local O
and O
national O
Parliaments B-ORGANIZATION
. O

Should O
the O
Herald B-ORGANIZATION
publish O
such O
advertisements O
? O

This O
is O
a O
difficult O
question O
. O

It O
would O
obviously O
be O
wrong O
to O
refuse O
all O
political O
advertisements O
with O
which O
we O
disagree O
. O

When O
an O
advertisement O
contains O
statements O
whose O
factual O
truth O
is O
doubtful O
, O
or O
where O
the O
total O
content O
would O
be O
deeply O
repugnant O
to O
our O
readers O
, O
it O
is O
right O
to O
exercise O
editorial O
discretion O
. O

The O
MRA B-ORGANIZATION
advertisement O
falls O
into O
neither O
category O
, O
though O
many O
readers O
will O
dislike O
it O
. O

The O
first B-CARDINAL
reaction O
of O
the O
Sudanese B-ORGANIZATION
Government I-ORGANIZATION
was O
to O
denounce O
the O
United B-ORGANIZATION
Nations I-ORGANIZATION
for O
" O
negligence O
and O
impotence O
, O
" O
and O
to O
say O
that O
its O
400 B-CARDINAL
troops O
in O
the O
Congo B-LOCATION
would O
be O
taken O
home O
. O

The O
reaction O
can O
be O
understood O
. O

The O
Sudan's B-LOCATION
concern O
for O
its O
men O
is O
natural O
. O

But O
this O
could O
hardly O
be O
a O
 O
dignified O
exit O
. O

IF O
the O
UN B-ORGANIZATION
is O
blamed O
for O
being O
weak O
, O
it O
would O
be O
more O
logical O
to O
send O
in O
more O
men O
, O
not O
weaken O
it O
further O
by O
desertion O
. O

It O
is O
unjust O
to O
pass O
the O
buck O
to O
Mr. O
Hammarskjold B-PERSON
and O
the O
UN's B-ORGANIZATION
servants O
. O

The O
responsibility O
rightly O
belongs O
to O
the O
nations O
which O
have O
undertaken O
the O
task O
of O
pre- O
serving O
peace O
in O
the O
Congo B-LOCATION
. O

That O
is O
not O
a O
ceremonial O
duty O
, O
and O
the O
soldiers O
have O
every O
right O
to O
blame O
the O
politicians O
unless O
they O
see O
it O
through O
. O

When O
the O
United B-ORGANIZATION
Nations I-ORGANIZATION
instructed O
Mr. O
Hammarskjold B-PERSON
to O
use O
force O
if O
necessary O
to O
prevent O
civil O
war O
, O
it O
was O
clear O
that O
new O
dangers O
would O
arise O
unless O
it O
gave O
him O
the O
political O
... O
That O
was O
the O
first B-CARDINAL
point O
that O
Mr. O
Hammarskjold B-PERSON
made O
. O

India B-LOCATION
has O
responded O
handsomely O
by O
providing O
3,000 B-CARDINAL
men O
, O
who O
must O
take O
about B-TIME
a I-TIME
fortnight I-TIME
to O
arrive O
. O

If O
the O
UN B-ORGANIZATION
forces O
were O
thick O
enough O
on O
the O
ground O
, O
such O
incidents O
as O
that O
at O
Matadi B-LOCATION
would O
not O
happen O
. O

THE O
UN's B-ORGANIZATION
ability O
to O
keep O
peace O
depends O
simply O
on O
adequate O
support O
by O
the O
nations O
which O
have O
set O
their O
hands O
to O
this O
plough O
. O

The O
big O
Powers O
involved O
in O
the O
Cold O
War O
must O
of O
course O
keep O
out O
. O

The O
Americans B-NORP
were O
justified O
in O
diverting O
naval O
ships O
in O
case O
non-combatant O
help O
was O
wanted O
; O
but O
they O
stressed O
that O
there O
was O
no O
intention O
to O
intervene O
in O
fighting O
. O

Yesterday B-TIME
the O
ships O
turned O
away O
again O
, O
satisfied O
that O
they O
were O
not O
required O
. O

It O
is O
to O
be O
hoped O
that O
the O
UN B-ORGANIZATION
will O
be O
re-established O
in O
their O
port O
by O
negotiation O
and O
that O
there O
will O
be O
no O
more O
outrages O
. O

But O
back O
, O
Mr. O
Hammarskjold B-PERSON
is O
determined O
, O
they O
must O
go O
. O

The O
best O
news O
for O
the O
Congo B-LOCATION
would O
be O
agreement O
between O
its O
rival O
political O
leaders O
. O

Through O
the O
patient O
efforts O
of O
UN B-ORGANIZATION
conciliators O
they O
are O
meeting O
for O
the O
first B-CARDINAL
time O
, O
in O
Malagasy B-LOCATION
( O
formerly O
Madagascar B-LOCATION
) O
. O

THE O
world O
will O
sigh O
with O
relief O
when O
this O
strife-torn O
land O
gets O
itself O
a O
government O
which O
all O
outsiders O
can O
recognise O
. O

ONLY O
a O
man O
wrapped O
in O
the O
impenetrable O
cocoon O
of O
what O
he O
regards O
as O
a O
divine O
mission O
could O
have O
spoken O
of O
apartheid O
as O
" O
a O
policy O
of O
good O
neighbourliness O
. O

" O
We O
may O
be O
sure O
that O
he O
is O
not O
being O
hypocritical O
. O

That O
is O
what O
he O
really O
believes O
. O

A O
good O
neighbour O
to O
those O
Africans B-NORP
who O
, O
under O
apartheid O
, O
will O
be O
forced O
back O
to O
their O
tribal O
reserves O
with O
no O
prospect O
but O
a O
cramped O
and O
primitive O
existence O
. O

A O
good O
neighbour O
to O
those O
Africans B-NORP
who O
will O
con- O
tinue O
to O
live O
as O
hewers O
of O
wood O
and O
drawers O
of O
water O
in O
the O
white O
areas O
of O
South B-LOCATION
Africa I-LOCATION
, O
without O
rights O
and O
without O
hope O
. O

THE O
same O
sort O
of O
good O
neighbour O
that O
he O
proved O
to O
be O
to O
the O
Jews B-NORP
fleeing O
from O
Hitler B-PERSON
in O
the B-TIME
thirties I-TIME
. O

It O
was O
Dr. O
Verwoerd B-PERSON
who O
led O
a O
protest O
against O
admitting O
any O
of O
them O
because O
they O
would O
" O
defile O
" O
the O
national O
white O
stock O
. O

It O
is O
impossible O
to O
make O
contact O
with O
Dr. O
Ver- B-PERSON
woerd I-PERSON
in O
his O
nightmare O
world O
. O

It O
is O
this O
that O
makes O
illusory O
any O
hopes O
that O
he O
may O
be O
in- O
fluenced O
to O
change O
course O
. O

The O
Archbishop O
of O
Capetown B-LOCATION
, O
Dr. O
Joost B-PERSON
de I-PERSON
Blank I-PERSON
, O
has O
pleaded O
that O
South B-LOCATION
Africa I-LOCATION
should O
be O
allowed O
to O
stay O
in O
the O
Commonwealth B-ORGANIZATION
. O

Otherwise O
, O
he O
says O
, O
those O
inside O
the O
country O
who O
still O
oppose O
apartheid O
will O
be O
left O
even O
more O
isolated O
and O
alone O
. O

The O
views O
of O
the O
Archbishop O
, O
who O
has O
maintained O
an O
unflinching O
witness O
to O
what O
Christianity B-ORGANIZATION
really O
means O
, O
must O
carry O
weight O
. O

But O
what O
, O
in O
fact O
, O
can O
the O
other O
Commonwealth B-ORGANIZATION
countries O
do O
to O
bring O
support O
and O
comfort O
to O
this O
gallant O
minority O
? O

THERE O
is O
no O
evidence O
that O
the O
policy O
of O
appeasement O
has O
modified O
the O
actions O
of O
the O
Nationalists B-NORP
. O

On O
the O
contrary O
, O
apartheid O
is O
being O
applied O
ever O
more O
ruthlessly O
. O

The O
shock O
of O
expulsion O
from O
the O
Commonwealth B-ORGANIZATION
now O
seems O
to O
be O
the O
only O
way O
left O
to O
try O
to O
bring O
home O
to O
the O
people O
of O
South B-LOCATION
Africa I-LOCATION
that O
Dr. O
Verwoerd B-PERSON
is O
leading O
them O
to O
disaster O
. O

It O
may O
be O
that O
the O
Commonwealth B-ORGANIZATION
Prime O
Ministers O
will O
decide O
against O
this O
final O
step O
. O

If O
that O
is O
their O
decision O
they O
should O
also O
go O
unequivocally O
on O
record O
that O
they O
regard O
apartheid O
as O
evil O
and O
indefensible O
. O

Unless O
they O
do O
at O
least O
that O
, O
Dr. O
Verwoerd B-PERSON
will O
be O
able O
to O
return O
home O
claiming O
a O
triumph O
. O

His O
smile O
will O
be O
blander O
than O
ever O
. O

WE O
are O
in O
for O
it O
again O
: O
another O
Royal O
Wedding O
. O

Between B-TIME
now I-TIME
and I-TIME
June I-TIME
, O
when O
the O
Duke O
of O
Kent B-LOCATION
will O
marry O
Miss O
Worsley B-PERSON
, O
hardly O
a B-TIME
day I-TIME
will O
pass O
without O
a O
story O
or O
a O
picture O
or O
probably O
both O
, O
about O
the O
nuptial O
arrangements O
. O

A O
BAFFLED O
and O
bewildered O
little O
country O
stands O
at O
the O
centre O
of O
an O
international O
storm O
. O

Belgium B-LOCATION
is O
accused O
- O
without O
a O
scrap O
of O
evidence O
- O
of O
being O
implicated O
in O
the O
murder O
of O
Patrice B-PERSON
Lumumba I-PERSON
. O

Her O
leaders O
are O
insulted O
, O
her O
embassies O
are O
attacked O
in O
a O
score O
of O
countries O
. O

In O
Ghana B-LOCATION
, O
President O
Nkrumah B-PERSON
, O
who O
has O
done O
more O
than O
most O
to O
stir O
up O
trouble O
in O
the O
Congo B-LOCATION
, O
orders O
every O
Belgian B-NORP
citizen O
to O
quit O
his O
country O
. O

HOUNDING O
Belgium B-LOCATION
has O
become O
an O
international O
pastime O
. O

Why O
? O

Because O
those O
who O
said O
the O
Congolese B-NORP
could O
govern O
themselves O
will O
not O
admit O
they O
were O
wrong O
. O

So O
Belgium B-LOCATION
, O
bowed O
down O
by O
internal O
troubles O
, O
mourning O
a O
terrible O
air O
crash O
, O
is O
made O
their O
scapegoat O
. O

Who O
will O
speak O
for O
Belgium B-LOCATION
? O

Who O
else O
but O
Britain B-LOCATION
. O

We O
have O
fought O
beside O
Belgium B-LOCATION
in O
two B-CARDINAL
world O
wars O
. O

We O
are O
allies O
still O
. O

Britain B-LOCATION
should O
champion O
Belgium B-LOCATION
. O

Not O
with O
the O
careful O
, O
hooded O
language O
of O
diplomacy O
, O
but O
boldly O
and O
fearlessly O
. O

It O
is O
time O
to O
show O
the O
world O
that O
this O
country O
does O
not O
desert O
her O
friends O
. O

HAPPY O
, O
happy O
families O
! O

Never O
before O
have O
Britain's B-LOCATION
larders O
been O
so O
well O
stocked O
. O

Supplies O
of O
meat O
and O
dairy O
produce O
were O
substantially O
higher O
last B-TIME
year I-TIME
than O
in O
1959 B-TIME
. O

Lucky O
, O
lucky O
housewives O
! O

To O
have O
such O
a O
splendid O
variety O
of O
goods O
to O
choose O
from O
. O

Not O
so O
long O
ago O
older O
folk O
were O
reminding O
young O
wives O
, O
 O
harassed O
by O
shortages O
, O
of O
the O
good O
old O
days O
of O
abundance O
. O

Now O
it O
is O
mother O
who O
picks O
up O
recipes O
from O
 O
her O
daughter O
. O

The O
dinner O
table O
is O
the O
best O
answer O
to O
the O
grumblers O
in O
Britain B-LOCATION
today B-TIME
! O

" O
THIS O
is O
colour O
day O
, O
" O
proclaimed O
the O
American B-NORP
television O
network O
, O
N.B.C. B-ORGANIZATION
And O
hour B-TIME
after I-TIME
hour I-TIME
it O
poured O
out O
its O
programmes O
in O
bright O
colours O
. O

In O
America B-LOCATION
colour O
TV O
is O
five B-TIME
years I-TIME
old I-TIME
. O

There O
are O
already O
600,000 B-CARDINAL
sets O
in O
use O
. O

What O
about O
Britain B-LOCATION
? O

The O
B.B.C. B-ORGANIZATION
is O
ready O
to O
launch O
a O
colour O
TV O
service O
, O
but O
the O
commercial O
TV O
contractors O
want O
to O
delay O
it O
for O
10 B-TIME
years I-TIME
. O

The O
Government B-ORGANIZATION
should O
settle O
this O
argument O
with O
two B-CARDINAL
words O
to O
the O
B.B.C. B-ORGANIZATION
: O
- O
Go O
ahead O
! O

ONE B-CARDINAL
man O
beyond O
all O
others O
is O
saddened O
by O
the O
deaths O
of O
two B-CARDINAL
elderly O
sisters O
who O
killed O
themselves O
because O
they O
had O
to O
leave O
their O
cottage O
. O

Mr. O
John B-PERSON
Crabb I-PERSON
, O
clerk O
to O
Newmarket B-LOCATION
urban B-ORGANIZATION
council I-ORGANIZATION
, O
says O
: O
" O
I O
shall O
always O
feel O
this O
as O
a O
personal O
failure O
. O

" O
There O
is O
no O
reason O
whatsoever O
why O
he O
should O
reproach O
himself O
. O

The O
sisters O
had O
to O
quit O
as O
their O
home O
was O
falling O
down O
. O

And O
Mr. O
Crabb B-PERSON
did O
his O
best O
for O
them O
, O
even O
driving O
them O
to O
a O
new O
house O
. O

John B-PERSON
Crabb I-PERSON
has O
the O
qualities O
of O
sympathy O
and O
understanding O
. O

Too O
often O
lacking O
in O
officialdom O
. O

MR. O
HENRY B-PERSON
NEWTON I-PERSON
of O
Acton B-LOCATION
does O
not O
want O
his O
daughter O
to O
marry O
a O
Scotsman B-NORP
. O

He O
says O
that O
the O
Scots B-NORP
are O
foreigners O
who O
have O
no O
business O
to O
be O
in O
England B-LOCATION
. O

The O
first B-CARDINAL
ruler O
of O
the O
United B-LOCATION
Kingdom I-LOCATION
was O
a O
Scot B-NORP
. O

The O
Lord O
Chancellor O
is O
a O
Scot B-NORP
. O

The O
Prime O
Minister O
is O
a O
Scot B-NORP
- O
and O
so O
were O
four B-CARDINAL
of O
his O
predecessors O
this B-TIME
 I-TIME
century I-TIME
. O

Let O
Mr. O
Newton B-PERSON
beware O
. O

By O
protesting O
against O
Scotland B-LOCATION
he O
may O
be O
guilty O
of O
rebellion O
! O

ARCHBISHOP O
MAKARIOS B-PERSON
puts O
the O
Commonwealth B-ORGANIZATION
on O
trial O
. O

His O
ex-Eoka B-ORGANIZATION
Government I-ORGANIZATION
decides O
that O
Cyprus B-LOCATION
will O
join O
it O
for O
five B-TIME
years I-TIME
. O

During O
this O
period O
Britain B-LOCATION
will O
be O
expected O
to O
subsidise O
and O
defend O
the O
Cypriots B-NORP
. O

They O
will O
enjoy O
all O
the O
trading O
benefits O
of O
Imperial O
Preference O
. O

It O
is O
a O
safe O
bet O
that O
at B-TIME
the I-TIME
end I-TIME
of I-TIME
five I-TIME
years I-TIME
Makarios B-PERSON
and O
company O
will O
sign O
on O
again O
. O

It O
is O
equally O
certain O
that O
the O
British B-ORGANIZATION
Government I-ORGANIZATION
will O
welcome O
them O
. O

How O
splendid O
it O
would O
be O
if O
, O
just O
for O
once O
, O
the O
Government B-ORGANIZATION
were O
to O
voice O
the O
real O
feelings O
of O
the O
British B-NORP
people O
. O

And O
tell O
Makarios B-PERSON
they O
are O
not O
prepared O
to O
accept O
him O
on O
such O
terms O
. O

GOOD O
cheer O
for O
the O
week-end B-TIME
. O

Ford B-ORGANIZATION
Motors I-ORGANIZATION
are O
to O
put O
13,000 B-CARDINAL
men O
back O
on O
a O
five-day B-TIME
week I-TIME
. O

One B-CARDINAL
more O
demonstration O
of O
the O
industry's O
recovery O
. O

As O
springtime B-TIME
approaches O
, O
orders O
pick O
up O
. O

And O
the O
car O
men O
get O
ready O
for O
another O
bustling O
season O
. O

The O
pessimists O
said O
the O
motor O
industry O
was O
on O
its O
knees O
. O

The O
optimists O
said O
" O
Nonsense O
. O

" O
As O
usual O
, O
the O
optimists O
have O
been O
proved O
right O
. O

EARL O
RUSSELL B-PERSON
and O
his O
friends O
have O
hit O
on O
an O
original O
way O
of O
spending O
this B-TIME
afternoon I-TIME
. O

They O
intend O
to O
sit O
outside O
the O
Ministry B-ORGANIZATION
of I-ORGANIZATION
Defence I-ORGANIZATION
. O

It O
is O
their O
protest O
against O
the O
H-bomb O
. O

They O
ought O
to O
have O
a O
pleasant O
time O
. O

The O
weather O
forecast O
is O
good O
; O
except O
for O
them O
, O
Whitehall B-LOCATION
should O
be O
deserted O
. O

And O
they O
will O
have O
a O
fine O
view O
of O
St. B-LOCATION
James's I-LOCATION
Park I-LOCATION
, O
with O
its O
placid O
lake O
, O
pelicans O
, O
rare O
ducks O
, O
and O
other O
wild O
life O
. O

Why O
not O
follow O
Lord O
Russell's B-PERSON
lead O
today B-TIME
? O

Head O
for O
the O
parks O
to O
enjoy O
the O
sun O
. O

Not O
in O
a O
foolish O
cause O
, O
but O
in O
a O
glorious O
one O
. O

Good O
health O
! O

THIS O
group O
of O
men O
, O
says O
a O
report O
, O
work O
on O
average O
between B-TIME
55 I-TIME
and I-TIME
60 I-TIME
hours I-TIME
a I-TIME
week I-TIME
. O

They O
also O
put O
in O
an O
extra O
two B-TIME
or I-TIME
three I-TIME
evenings I-TIME
. O

And O
they O
never O
go O
on O
strike O
. O

Who O
are O
they O
? O

The O
trade O
union O
officials O
of O
Britain B-LOCATION
. O

Men O
who O
earn O
only O
a O
fraction O
of O
what O
their O
talents O
and O
responsibilities O
could O
bring O
in O
the O
open O
labour O
market O
. O

The O
unions O
are O
fortunate O
indeed O
to O
find O
dedicated O
leaders O
at O
cut-rate O
prices O
. O

But O
it O
is O
time O
the O
members O
decided O
to O
pay O
up O
and O
be O
good O
employers O
. O

THE O
Labour B-ORGANIZATION
Party I-ORGANIZATION
says O
that O
the O
Tory B-ORGANIZATION
Government I-ORGANIZATION
is O
destroying O
the O
social O
services O
. O

Under O
the O
Labour B-ORGANIZATION
Government I-ORGANIZATION
18.1 B-CARDINAL
per O
cent O
of O
the O
national O
income O
was O
spent O
on O
social O
services O
. O

The O
present O
figure O
is O
19.5 B-CARDINAL
per O
cent. O
There O
are O
many O
worthwhile O
targets O
for O
the O
Opposition B-ORGANIZATION
. O

What O
a O
pity O
to O
aim O
at O
the O
wrong O
one O
! O

MRS. O
MARCIA B-PERSON
POWER I-PERSON
, O
whose O
husband O
made O
her O
clean O
his O
uniform O
, O
wins O
a O
divorce O
. O

The O
judge O
says O
she O
had O
to O
act O
almost O
as O
a O
serf O
. O

Up O
and O
down O
the O
country O
husbands O
will O
be O
saying O
they O
would O
never O
behave O
like O
that O
. O

But O
do O
they O
ever O
ponder O
how O
their O
gardening O
tools O
are O
mysteriously O
returned O
to O
the O
shed O
; O
their O
books O
tidied O
; O
and O
often O
, O
even O
their O
shoes O
cleaned O
? O

How O
wonderful O
if O
they O
showed O
their O
appreciation O
this B-TIME
morning I-TIME
with O
a O
surprise O
box O
of O
chocolates O
or O
a O
bunch O
of O
flowers O
! O

CONTRAST O
his O
firm O
, O
successful O
rule O
in O
Rhodesia B-LOCATION
with O
what O
has O
happened O
in O
the O
Congo B-LOCATION
. O

There O
Welensky's B-PERSON
opponents O
have O
carried O
their O
theories O
into O
practice O
. O

There O
a O
UNO B-ORGANIZATION
army O
of O
Africans B-NORP
, O
bossed O
by O
an O
Indian B-NORP
, O
has O
been O
in O
charge O
for O
months B-TIME
. O

And O
what O
has O
it O
made O
of O
the O
Congo B-LOCATION
? O

A O
bloodstained O
shambles O
. O

No O
wonder O
Welensky B-PERSON
has O
lost O
all O
patience O
with O
his O
misguided O
tormentors O
. O

They O
have O
earned O
his O
strictures O
. O

And O
his O
contempt O
. O

SOME O
people O
are O
for O
ever O
complaining O
that O
teenagers O
earn O
too O
much O
and O
spend O
it O
all O
when O
they O
get O
it O
. O

Now O
a O
survey O
of O
the O
Post B-ORGANIZATION
Office I-ORGANIZATION
Savings I-ORGANIZATION
Bank I-ORGANIZATION
shows O
how O
wrong O
that O
idea O
is O
. O

The O
biggest O
group O
of O
depositors O
in O
the O
bank O
is O
made O
of O
boys O
and O
girls O
aged O
15 B-TIME
to I-TIME
19 I-TIME
. O

Certainly O
teenagers O
earn O
more O
than O
ever O
before O
. O

Certainly O
they O
spend O
more O
. O

But O
how O
splendid O
that O
in O
the O
most O
prosperous O
days O
in O
this O
country's O
history O
the O
old-fashioned O
virtue O
of O
thrift O
should O
still O
have O
a O
powerful O
appeal O
for O
young O
people O
. O

THE O
Danes B-NORP
are O
annoyed O
with O
British B-NORP
farmers O
for O
fighting O
against O
Danish B-NORP
competition O
. O

They O
say O
that O
our O
farmers O
do O
not O
seem O
to O
understand O
the O
meaning O
of O
free O
trade O
. O

There O
is O
no O
doubt O
what O
the O
Danes B-NORP
understand O
by O
free O
trade O
. O

It O
is O
that O
they O
should O
be O
free O
to O
sell O
as O
much O
as O
they O
like O
, O
while O
buying O
more O
and O
more O
from O
our O
rivals O
. O

Germany B-LOCATION
has O
now O
supplanted O
Britain B-LOCATION
as O
Denmark's B-LOCATION
principal O
supplier O
. O

The O
farmers O
of O
Britain B-LOCATION
understand O
free O
trade O
. O

That O
is O
why O
they O
fight O
it O
. O

THE O
Palace B-LOCATION
cinema I-LOCATION
at O
Buckley B-LOCATION
, O
near O
Chester B-LOCATION
, O
will O
be O
reopened O
next B-TIME
week I-TIME
by O
Barry B-PERSON
Flanagan I-PERSON
and O
Eric B-PERSON
Platt I-PERSON
, O
both O
aged O
19 B-TIME
. O

Eric B-PERSON
says O
: O
" O
We O
believe O
in O
the O
cinema O
. O

And O
we O
know O
what O
people O
want O
. O

" O
The O
combination O
of O
enthusiasm O
and O
shrewd O
anticipation O
of O
public O
taste O
has O
launched O
many O
great O
enterprises O
. O

Barry B-PERSON
and O
Eric B-PERSON
have O
enthusiasm O
. O

They O
are O
backed O
by O
a O
resurgent O
film O
industry O
. O

It O
could O
be O
curtain O
up O
on O
two B-CARDINAL
success O
stories O
. O

Of O
the O
old O
Palace B-LOCATION
. O

And O
Barry B-PERSON
and O
Eric B-PERSON
. O

DONS O
at O
Cambridge B-ORGANIZATION
want O
the O
study O
of O
agriculture O
to O
become O
an O
honours O
degree O
course O
. O

Farming O
is O
Britain's B-LOCATION
most O
vital O
industry O
. O

It O
is O
increasingly O
dependent O
on O
new O
techniques O
- O
and O
on O
the O
universities O
to O
provide O
men O
of O
knowledge O
and O
skill O
. O

The O
older O
universities O
are O
often O
accused O
of O
being O
interested O
only O
in O
dead O
subjects O
. O

Now O
Cambridge B-ORGANIZATION
has O
the O
opportunity O
to O
show O
is O
just O
as O
interested O
in O
the O
living O
. O

Particularly O
as O
its O
rival O
, O
Oxford B-ORGANIZATION
, O
has O
had O
a O
similar O
course O
in O
farming O
for O
15 B-TIME
years I-TIME
! O

JOHN B-PERSON
GLENN I-PERSON
, O
Virgil B-PERSON
Grissom I-PERSON
, O
Alan B-PERSON
Shepard I-PERSON
. O

One B-CARDINAL
of O
these O
three B-CARDINAL
men O
has O
a O
date O
with O
destiny O
- O
the O
first B-CARDINAL
journey O
into O
Space O
. O

At O
the B-TIME
beginning I-TIME
of I-TIME
this I-TIME
wonderful I-TIME
century I-TIME
many O
people O
believed O
that O
there O
were O
no O
more O
worlds O
to O
conquer O
. O

Hence O
the O
hostility O
to O
automation O
and O
the O
stop-watch O
manufacturing O
methods O
that O
have O
 O
led O
to O
restrictive O
practices O
. O

Now O
a O
new O
threat O
to O
those O
who O
toil O
and O
spin O
has O
been O
developed O
by O
a O
firm O
specialising O
in O
electronics O
in O
Los B-LOCATION
Angeles I-LOCATION
. O

They O
have O
developed O
a O
new O
system O
whereby O
completely O
untrained O
workers O
can O
be O
taught O
their O
trade O
by O
means O
of O
tape O
recordings O
and O
television O
. O

What O
happens O
is O
that O
the O
unskilled O
worker O
is O
processed O
, O
by O
high-speed O
listening O
to O
recorded O
instructions O
on O
how O
to O
do O
the O
job O
coupled O
with O
explanatory O
TV O
pictures O
, O
into O
becoming O
a O
highly O
skilled O
, O
obedient O
craftsman O
in O
no O
time O
at O
all O
. O

Not O
only O
can O
the O
raw O
human O
mind O
be O
technically O
equipped O
very O
quickly O
to O
do O
one B-CARDINAL
set O
of O
skilled O
manufacturing O
processes O
in O
one B-CARDINAL
trade O
but O
, O
by O
being O
given O
another O
of O
the O
new O
audio-TV O
training O
techniques O
, O
he O
can O
be O
switched O
to O
a O
different O
industry O
if O
he O
just O
gives O
in O
and O
From O
being O
an O
assembler O
in O
an O
aircraft O
factory O
to O
becoming O
a O
paint O
sprayer O
in O
a O
ceramic O
factory O
, O
he O
can O
be O
qualified O
for O
a O
completely O
new O
job O
in O
less O
time O
than O
it O
takes O
to O
say O
" O
Tolpuddle B-LOCATION
Martyrs O
! O

" O
" O
CRICKET O
, O
" O
says O
the O
Oxford B-ORGANIZATION
Dictionary O
, O
is O
" O
an O
open O
air O
game O
played O
with O
ball O
, O
bats O
and O
wickets O
between O
 O
two B-CARDINAL
sides O
consisting O
of O
eleven B-CARDINAL
players O
each O
. O

" O
Not O
so O
, O
dear O
Oxford B-ORGANIZATION
Dictionary O
. O

You O
are O
out O
of O
date O
. O

Cricket O
in O
1961 B-TIME
is O
played O
with O
a O
theodolite O
, O
six B-CARDINAL
surveyors O
, O
a O
ball O
; O
bats O
and O
wickets O
between O
two B-CARDINAL
sides O
. O

Shades O
of O
the O
village O
stalwarts O
of O
Hambledon B-LOCATION
who O
are O
now O
the O
patron O
saints O
of O
the O
game O
! O

What O
would O
THEY O
have O
thought O
of O
these O
civil O
engineers O
creeping O
about O
the O
pitch O
with O
their O
optical O
instruments O
? O

The O
village O
green O
is O
the O
real O
home O
of O
cricket O
. O

A O
couple O
of O
bumps O
on O
a O
pitch O
have O
no O
terrors O
for O
a O
good O
batsman O
with O
a O
stout O
heart O
, O
a O
firm O
grip O
on O
the O
willow O
and O
a O
hefty O
contempt O
for O
batting O
averages O
and O
all O
the O
statistical O
blight O
that O
makes O
a O
mighty O
six B-CARDINAL
these O
days O
as O
rare O
as O
frostbite O
in O
summer B-TIME
. O

They O
'll O
be O
clapping O
the O
man O
who O
plays O
a O
straight O
theodolite O
next O
. O

EICHMANN B-PERSON
continues O
 O
to O
reveal O
the O
extraordinary O
divisions O
of O
the O
German B-NORP
mind O
. O

Not O
content O
with O
arguing O
that O
he O
was O
only O
an O
efficient O
cog O
in O
the O
machine O
, O
he O
now O
claims O
that O
part O
of O
the O
endless O
massacre O
that O
led O
to O
the O
death O
of O
six B-CARDINAL
million I-CARDINAL
Jews B-NORP
was O
" O
decent O
, O
feasible O
and O
workable O
. O

" O
He O
feels O
satisfaction O
" O
from O
the O
fact O
that O
my O
personality O
had O
been O
tested O
and O
weighed O
and O
not O
found O
wanting O
. O

" O
He O
feels O
like O
Pontius B-PERSON
Pilate I-PERSON
who O
washed O
his O
hands O
before O
the O
multitude O
saying O
: O
" O
I O
am O
innocent O
of O
the O
blood O
of O
this O
just O
person O
. O

" O
Like O
Dr. O
Globke B-PERSON
, O
whom O
I O
interviewed O
the O
other O
day O
, O
Eichmann B-PERSON
said O
: O
" O
I O
drew O
a O
certain O
solace O
from O
the O
fact O
that O
I O
did O
what O
I O
could O
despite O
my O
low O
rank O
. O

" O
Eichmann B-PERSON
is O
on O
dangerous O
ground O
when O
he O
pleads O
that O
he O
was O
only O
a O
small O
unit O
on O
the O
base O
of O
the O
triangle O
that O
led O
to O
Hitler B-PERSON
, O
Himmler B-PERSON
, O
Hess B-PERSON
and O
Goering B-PERSON
at O
the O
apex O
. O

In O
examination O
he O
betrayed O
an O
expert O
and O
intimate O
knowledge O
of O
every O
link O
in O
the O
chain O
of O
command O
that O
led O
to O
the O
top O
. O

He O
understood O
the O
whole O
apparatus O
with O
an O
exact O
and O
meticulous O
comprehension O
that O
could O
only O
have O
come O
from O
a O
man O
who O
used O
the O
system O
- O
and O
used O
it O
with O
power O
and O
authority O
. O

The O
appalling O
thing O
about O
the O
Germans B-NORP
is O
that O
they O
can O
kid O
them- O
selves O
and O
feel O
a O
sense O
of O
righteousness O
when O
their O
hands O
are O
red O
with O
blood O
. O

" O
Without O
Britain's B-LOCATION
tolerance O
German B-NORP
rearma- O
ment O
in O
the O
air O
would O
be O
jeopardised O
. O

" O
When O
Hoesch's B-PERSON
reports O
, O
along O
with O
other O
nazi B-NORP
documents O
, O
were O
captured O
and O
published O
after O
the O
war O
the O
pattern O
of O
British B-ORGANIZATION
Government I-ORGANIZATION
connivance O
became O
clear O
. O

At O
nazi B-LOCATION
Germany's I-LOCATION
request O
, O
Britain B-LOCATION
was O
providing O
the O
cloak O
for O
Germany B-LOCATION
to O
build O
an O
air O
force O
bigger O
than O
that O
of O
France B-LOCATION
. O

Yesterday B-TIME
West B-NORP
German I-NORP
Defence O
Minister O
, O
Herr O
Strauss B-PERSON
, O
started O
talks O
with O
the O
British B-NORP
Defence O
Minister O
, O
Mr. O
Watkinson B-PERSON
. O

Their O
talks O
are O
another O
stage O
in O
the O
cloak O
operation O
, O
1961 B-TIME
variety O
, O
by O
which O
the O
West B-NORP
German I-NORP
militarists O
are O
advancing O
their O
rearmament O
. O

Herr O
Strauss B-PERSON
told O
the O
Daily B-ORGANIZATION
Mail I-ORGANIZATION
last B-TIME
October I-TIME
that O
his O
policy O
was O
to O
make O
his O
country O
the O
" O
strongest O
militarily O
in O
Europe B-LOCATION
and O
the O
United B-LOCATION
States' I-LOCATION
principal O
Nato B-ORGANIZATION
ally O
. O

" O
The O
process O
has O
been O
too O
slow O
for O
Herr O
Strauss B-PERSON
and O
last B-TIME
month I-TIME
he O
attacked O
Britain B-LOCATION
for O
being O
an O
obstacle O
for O
West B-LOCATION
Germany's I-LOCATION
plans O
for O
a O
" O
unified O
supply O
apparatus O
" O
in O
Nato B-ORGANIZATION
. O

( O
A O
supply O
apparatus O
which O
would O
link O
together O
the O
various O
West B-NORP
German I-NORP
" O
facilities O
. O

" O
) O
By O
the O
end B-TIME
of I-TIME
the I-TIME
year I-TIME
there O
will O
be O
11 B-CARDINAL
German B-NORP
divisions O
in O
Nato B-ORGANIZATION
compared O
with O
four B-CARDINAL
divisions O
of O
British B-NORP
troops O
. O

When O
Scarborough B-LOCATION
carried O
our O
point O
of O
view O
we O
were O
naturally O
delighted O
, O
more O
so O
because O
the O
alternatives O
had O
been O
put O
clearly O
to O
the O
movement O
, O
which O
had O
then O
chosen O
a O
vigorous O
anti-Nato B-NORP
, O
anti-Tory B-NORP
, O
anti-bomb B-NORP
and O
anti-German B-NORP
rearmament O
policy O
. O

Hopes O
rose O
as O
we O
saw O
a O
perspective O
of O
sharp O
struggle O
based O
on O
consistent O
lines O
of O
difference O
with O
the O
Tories B-NORP
. O

Many O
members O
understood O
that O
the O
bread-and-butter O
struggles O
of O
the O
union O
would O
become O
easier O
in O
the O
context O
They O
obstructed O
every O
effort O
to O
fight O
for O
the O
Scarborough B-LOCATION
decisions O
, O
while O
 O
scratching O
around O
frantically O
to O
overturn O
them O
next O
time O
. O

Confusion O
of O
the O
original O
issue O
by O
misrepresentation O
of O
the O
decisions O
, O
the O
introduction O
of O
a O
pseudo O
third B-CARDINAL
way O
and O
the O
call O
for O
party O
unity O
- O
in O
effect O
, O
a O
demand O
that O
the O
movement O
unite O
with O
the O
Gaitskellites B-NORP
on O
their O
policy O
and O
no O
other O
seems O
to O
have O
done O
the O
trick O
of O
moving O
a O
number O
of O
unions O
Ordinary O
working O
people O
will O
never O
rally O
to O
defend O
a O
policy O
founded O
on O
political O
chicanery O
or O
elect O
a O
Labour B-ORGANIZATION
Government I-ORGANIZATION
to O
carry O
through O
Tory B-ORGANIZATION
policy O
- O
Gaitskell's B-PERSON
stupid O
hope O
. O

The O
tragedy O
is O
that O
enormous O
inroads O
could O
already O
have O
been O
made O
into O
Tory B-ORGANIZATION
strength O
by O
a O
fighting O
policy O
, O
based O
on O
Scarborough B-LOCATION
. O

THE O
desire O
for O
unity O
in O
the O
Labour O
and O
trade O
union O
movement O
following O
the O
At O
the O
same O
time O
that O
unity O
cannot O
be O
established O
on O
a O
false O
basis O
, O
or O
by O
creating O
further O
confusion O
within O
the O
movement O
. O

Unity O
will O
never O
be O
established O
on O
the O
basis O
of O
leaders O
being O
a O
law O
unto O
themselves O
and O
opposing O
conference O
decisions O
when O
it O
suits O
their O
own O
convenience O
. O

Unity O
can O
never O
be O
established O
by O
any O
formula O
uniting O
those O
who O
oppose O
German B-NORP
troops O
being O
trained O
on O
British B-NORP
soil O
and O
Polaris O
, O
and O
those O
who O
are O
for O
this O
policy O
- O
which O
is O
the O
same O
as O
that O
of O
the O
Tory B-ORGANIZATION
Government I-ORGANIZATION
. O

This O
should O
strengthen O
the O
campaign O
to O
end O
the O
manufacture O
and O
use O
of O
nuclear O
weapons O
in O
Britain B-LOCATION
. O

Britain B-LOCATION
then O
could O
play O
a O
leading O
and O
independent O
role O
for O
an O
international O
agreement O
to O
ban O
all O
nuclear O
strategy O
and O
weapons O
of O
mass O
destruction O
, O
and O
lay O
the O
basis O
for O
real O
peace O
and O
progress O
. O

WHEN O
all O
the O
ballyhoo O
about O
Commonwealth B-ORGANIZATION
Training O
Week O
subsides O
it O
is O
doubtful O
whether O
more O
than O
a O
handful O
of O
new O
apprenticeships O
The O
film O
version O
of O
Miss O
Shelagh B-PERSON
Delaney's I-PERSON
play O
A O
Taste O
of O
Honey O
opens O
at O
the O
Leicester B-LOCATION
Square I-LOCATION
Theatre I-LOCATION
tomorrow B-TIME
. O

It O
has O
been O
produced O
an O
directed O
by O
Mr. O
Tony B-PERSON
Richardson I-PERSON
, O
who O
is O
also O
part-author O
with O
Miss O
Delaney B-PERSON
of O
the O
script O
, O
and O
the O
great O
advantages O
to O
be O
derived O
from O
this O
unity O
of O
conception O
and O
control O
are O
everywhere O
apparent O
. O

The O
film O
version O
of O
Miss O
Shelagh B-PERSON
Delaney's I-PERSON
play O
A O
Taste O
of O
Honey O
opens O
at O
the O
Leicester B-LOCATION
Square I-LOCATION
Theatre I-LOCATION
tomorrow B-TIME
. O

It O
has O
been O
produced O
and O
directed O
by O
Mr. O
Tony B-PERSON
Richardson I-PERSON
, O
who O
is O
also O
part-author O
with O
Miss O
Delaney B-PERSON
of O
the O
script O
, O
and O
the O
great O
advantages O
to O
be O
derived O
from O
this O
unity O
of O
conception O
and O
control O
are O
everywhere O
apparent O
. O

The O
film O
version O
of O
Miss O
Shelagh B-PERSON
Delaney's I-PERSON
play O
A O
Taste O
of O
Honey O
opens O
at O
the O
Leicester B-LOCATION
Square I-LOCATION
Theatre I-LOCATION
tomorrow B-TIME
. O

It O
has O
been O
produced O
and O
directed O
by O
Mr. O
Tony B-PERSON
Richardson I-PERSON
, O
who O
is O
also O
part- O
author O
with O
Miss O
Delaney B-PERSON
of O
the O
script O
, O
and O
the O
great O
advantages O
to O
be O
derived O
from O
this O
unity O
of O
conception O
and O
control O
are O
everywhere O
apparent O
. O

The O
film O
version O
of O
Miss O
Shelagh B-PERSON
Delaney's I-PERSON
play O
A O
Taste O
of O
Honey O
opens O
at O
the O
Leicester B-LOCATION
Square I-LOCATION
Theatre I-LOCATION
tomorrow B-TIME
. O

It O
has O
been O
pro- O
duced O
and O
directed O
by O
Mr. O
Tony B-PERSON
Richardson I-PERSON
, O
who O
is O
also O
part-author O
with O
Miss O
Delaney B-PERSON
of O
the O
script O
, O
and O
the O
great O
advantages O
to O
be O
derived O
from O
this O
unity O
of O
conception O
and O
control O
are O
everywhere O
apparent O
. O

The O
film O
version O
of O
Miss O
Shelagh B-PERSON
Delaney's I-PERSON
play O
A O
Taste O
of O
Honey O
opens O
at O
the O
Leicester B-LOCATION
Square I-LOCATION
Theatre I-LOCATION
tomorrow B-TIME
. O

It O
has O
been O
produced O
and O
directed O
by O
Mr. O
Tony B-PERSON
Richardson I-PERSON
, O
who O
is O
also O
part-author O
with O
Miss O
Delaney B-PERSON
of O
the O
script O
, O
and O
the O
great O
advantages O
to O
be O
derived O
from O
this O
unity O
of O
conception O
and O
control O
are O
everywhere O
apparent O
. O

The O
film O
version O
of O
Miss O
Shelagh B-PERSON
Delaney's I-PERSON
play O
A O
Taste O
of O
Honey O
opens O
at O
the O
Leicester B-LOCATION
Square I-LOCATION
Theatre I-LOCATION
tomorrow B-TIME
. O
